<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-12-20T18:02:38+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A data-driven literature for understudied genes. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">TP53</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/TP53/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TP53"/><published>2024-12-19T21:21:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-19T21:21:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/TP53</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/TP53/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/7157">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">7157</td> <td style="text-align: left">TP53</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000141510</td> <td style="text-align: left">17p13.1</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene is involved in various biological processes, including <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0000122">negative regulation of transcription by RNA polymerase II</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0000423">mitophagy</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0000785">chromatin</a> organization. It enables functions such as <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0000976">transcription cis-regulatory region binding</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0000978">RNA polymerase II cis-regulatory region sequence-specific DNA binding</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0000981">DNA-binding transcription factor activity, RNA polymerase II-specific</a>. The gene is located in the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005634">nucleus</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005654">nucleoplasm</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005737">cytoplasm</a>, and is part of the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005667">transcription regulator complex</a> and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0032991">protein-containing complex</a>. Additionally, it plays roles in processes like <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0001701">in utero embryonic development</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0001756">somitogenesis</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0001836">release of cytochrome c from mitochondria</a>, among others. The gene is also involved in the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0006974">DNA damage response</a> and acts upstream of or within the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0006983">ER overload response</a>. Furthermore, it enables binding activities such as <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0002020">protease binding</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0002039">p53 binding</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0003677">DNA binding</a>. The gene is involved in the regulation of various processes, including <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0006357">transcription by RNA polymerase II</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0043065">apoptotic process</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0051726">cell cycle</a>, among others.</p> <p>The gene length is 22,917 base pairs (45.33% of all genes), the mature length is 3,253 base pairs, and the primary transcript length is 22,907 base pairs (55.35% of all genes).</p> <p>The gene TP53 (NCBI ID: 7157) has been mentioned in <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22TP53%22">21,550 publications</a> (note: the count in the hyperlink may be different since the count is from <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>). The earliest year of publication mentioning TP53 is 1981, and the middle 50% of publications occurred between 1999 and 2016.</p> <p>The top five publications mentioning TP53, ranked by their scientific influence, include “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1905840">p53 mutations in human cancers.</a>” (1991) with a <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">Relative Citation Ratio (RCR)</a> of 189.18, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8242752">WAF1, a potential mediator of p53 tumor suppression.</a>” (1993) with an RCR of 177.23, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1614522">Cancer. p53, guardian of the genome.</a>” (1992) with an RCR of 102.85, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2046748">The p53 tumour suppressor gene.</a>” (1991) with an RCR of 97.42, and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1933891">Participation of p53 protein in the cellular response to DNA damage.</a>” (1991) with an RCR of 92.1. The Relative Citation Ratio (RCR) measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p><a href="https://www.proteinatlas.org/ENSG00000141510-TP53">TP53</a> is a multifunctional gene with roles as an activator, DNA-binding protein, and repressor. It is implicated in various diseases, including cancer-related genes, disease variants, Li-Fraumeni syndrome, and functions as a tumor suppressor. Evidence for its function is available at the protein level. TP53 is detected in all tissues and is primarily localized in the nucleoplasm, vesicles, and cytosol. Its expression is associated with Cluster 13 in blood, Cluster 36 in lymphoid tissue, Cluster 44 in the brain, Cluster 42 in cell lines, and Cluster 16 in single cells, specifically intestinal goblet cells involved in mucin production.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/9126">SMC3</a> with 6 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2313">FLI1</a> with 5 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/23476">BRD4</a> with 4 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2626">GATA4</a> with 4 experiments, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2624">GATA2</a> with 4 experiments. These TFs have been shown to play significant roles in gene regulation, as evidenced by their frequent appearance in CHIP-seq data.</p> <p>The GWAS data indicates associations with various disease conditions, including several types of cancer such as integumentary system cancer, skin cancer, skin carcinoma, basal cell carcinoma, pigmented basal cell carcinoma, breast cancer, thoracic cancer, and organ system cancer. Additionally, the data highlights associations with nephrosis, nephrotic syndrome, kidney disease, and urinary system disease. Cardiovascular conditions such as coronary artery disease, artery disease, vascular disease, cardiovascular system disease, and myocardial infarction are also implicated. Furthermore, the data includes associations with hematopoietic system disease, immune system disease, hypersensitivity reaction disease, hypersensitivity reaction type II disease, and general categories such as disease of cellular proliferation and disease of anatomical entity.</p> <p>The TP53 gene has been associated with various traits and diseases through genome-wide association studies. Notably, it has been linked to <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33462484">Apolipoprotein B levels</a>, which maps closely to <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D001053">Apolipoproteins</a> using the BioWordVec method. Additionally, TP53 is associated with <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/36502284">Body surface area</a>, directly matching the MeSH term <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D001830">Body Surface Area</a>. Other associations include <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33462484">Glycated hemoglobin levels</a>, mapping to <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D006454">Hemoglobins</a>, and <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33462484">Low density lipoprotein cholesterol levels</a>, mapping to <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D008074">Lipoproteins</a>. Furthermore, TP53 is linked to <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31624269">Mosaic loss of chromosome Y (Y chromosome dosage)</a>, mapping to <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D002875">Chromosomes</a>, and various protein-related traits such as <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33462484">Non-albumin protein levels</a>, mapping to <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D011506">Proteins</a>, and <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33462484">Serum total protein levels</a>, mapping to <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D044967">Serum</a>. Other notable associations include <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33462484">Sex hormone-binding globulin levels</a>, mapping to <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D005916">Globulins</a>, <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33462484">Testosterone levels</a>, mapping to <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D013739">Testosterone</a>, and <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33462484">Triglyceride levels</a>, mapping to <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D014280">Triglycerides</a>.</p> <p>The gene is expressed in various tissues, including the ovary, skin, and spleen, as indicated by the BioGPS Human Cell Type and Tissue Gene Expression Profiles. Additionally, the GTEx Tissue Gene Expression Profiles show expression in cardiac myocytes, B lymphoblasts, promyelocytic leukemia cells (HL-60), Burkitt’s lymphoma cells (Daudi), smooth muscle, colorectal adenocarcinoma, and the thymus.</p> <p>The input data highlights various pathways involved in cellular senescence, stress responses, and cell cycle regulation. Key pathways include DNA damage/telomere stress-induced senescence, formation of senescence-associated heterochromatin foci (SAHF), and oxidative stress-induced senescence. Additionally, the data covers signaling pathways such as NOTCH signaling and its pre-expression and processing, as well as oncogene-induced senescence. Cell cycle regulation is represented through pathways like G1/S DNA damage checkpoints, p53-dependent G1 DNA damage response, and general cell cycle checkpoints. Apoptosis and programmed cell death pathways are also included, along with hemostasis and signal transduction processes. Specific mechanisms such as the activation of BH3-only proteins, NOXA, and PUMA, as well as the transcriptional activation of p21 and p53 responsive genes, are noted.</p> <p>The mouse ortholog gene 22059, which corresponds to the human ortholog gene 7157, is associated with several phenotypic abnormalities. These include abnormal retina morphology, increased startle reflex, persistence of the hyaloid vascular system, and preweaning lethality with incomplete penetrance. All these phenotypes are observed in both sexes.</p> <p>The analyzed protein sequence has a GRAVY value of -0.756 (14.0% percentile), indicating a hydrophilic nature. The charge at pH 7.0 is -3.47 (37.98% percentile), and the median structural flexibility is 1.01 (80.48% percentile). The protein has a high instability index of 73.59 (96.4% percentile) and an isoelectric point of 6.33 (38.94% percentile). The sequence length is 393 amino acids (44.33% percentile) with a molecular weight of 43652.71 Da (44.15% percentile). The secondary structure affinities are 30.03% for helix (32.26% percentile), 26.46% for sheet (12.58% percentile), and 35.62% for turn (90.94% percentile). These calculations were performed using <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython’s sequence analysis tools</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">yes</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="test"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[TP53 description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">An example with chart</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/echarts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An example with chart"/><published>2024-01-26T16:03:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-26T16:03:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/echarts</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/echarts/"><![CDATA[<p>This is an example post with some <a href="https://echarts.apache.org/">echarts</a> code.</p> <div class="language-markdown highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="p">```</span><span class="nl">echarts
</span><span class="sb">{
  "title": {
    "text": "ECharts Getting Started Example"
  },
  "responsive": true,
  "tooltip": {},
  "legend": {
    "top": "30px",
    "data": ["sales"]
  },
  "xAxis": {
    "data": ["Shirts", "Cardigans", "Chiffons", "Pants", "Heels", "Socks"]
  },
  "yAxis": {},
  "series": [
    {
      "name": "sales",
      "type": "bar",
      "data": [5, 20, 36, 10, 10, 20]
    }
  ]
}</span>
<span class="p">```</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p>Which generates:</p> <pre><code class="language-echarts">{
  "title": {
    "text": "ECharts Getting Started Example"
  },
  "responsive": true,
  "tooltip": {},
  "legend": {
    "top": "30px",
    "data": ["sales"]
  },
  "xAxis": {
    "data": ["Shirts", "Cardigans", "Chiffons", "Pants", "Heels", "Socks"]
  },
  "yAxis": {},
  "series": [
    {
      "name": "sales",
      "type": "bar",
      "data": [5, 20, 36, 10, 10, 20]
    }
  ]
}
</code></pre> <p>Note that this library offer support for both light and dark themes. You can switch between them using the theme switcher in the top right corner of the page.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Uses echart js library]]></summary></entry></feed>