<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-12-09T15:32:53+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A data-driven literature for understudied genes. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">AAAS</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/AAAS/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AAAS"/><published>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/AAAS</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/AAAS/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/8086">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">8086</td> <td style="text-align: left">AAAS</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000094914</td> <td style="text-align: left">12q13.13</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene length is 878,010 base pairs (99.45% of all genes), the mature length is 4,948.5 base pairs, and the primary transcript length is 573,840 base pairs (99.46% of all genes).</p> <p>The gene AAAS, with NCBI ID 8086, has been the subject of <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22AAAS%22">94 publications</a> (note: count may differ as it is sourced from <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>). The earliest year of publication is 1948, and the middle 50% of publications occurred between 1986 and 2010.</p> <p>The top five publications mentioning the AAAS gene, ranked by their scientific influence, include “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11159947">Triple A syndrome is caused by mutations in AAAS, a new WD-repeat protein gene.</a>” (2001) with a <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">Relative Citation Ratio (RCR)</a> of 3.43, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12730363">The nuclear pore complex protein ALADIN is mislocalized in triple A syndrome.</a>” (2003) with an RCR of 2.16, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16609705">Cellular localization of 17 natural mutant variants of ALADIN protein in triple A syndrome - shedding light on an unexpected splice mutation.</a>” (2006) with an RCR of 1.2, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11701718">Spectrum of mutations of the AAAS gene in Allgrove syndrome: lack of mutations in six kindreds with isolated resistance to corticotropin.</a>” (2001) with an RCR of 1.14, and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26246606">The nucleoporin ALADIN regulates Aurora A localization to ensure robust mitotic spindle formation.</a>” (2015) with an RCR of 1.13. The Relative Citation Ratio (RCR) measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD database, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/5970">RELA</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/5978">REST</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/1876">E2F6</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/5241">PGR</a>, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/7227">TRPS1</a>, each shown to be regulating in 5 experiments.</p> <p>The analyzed protein sequence has a GRAVY value of -0.084 (79.18th percentile), indicating a hydrophilic nature. At pH 7.0, the protein carries a charge of 0.995 (53.96th percentile). The median structural flexibility is 0.997 (26.57th percentile), with a secondary structure composition of 26.2% helix (8.38th percentile), 36.8% sheet (71.81st percentile), and 33.5% turn (84.14th percentile). The instability index is 43.73 (34.71st percentile), and the isoelectric point is 7.26 (52.82nd percentile). The protein is 546 amino acids long (63.7th percentile) with a molecular weight of 59573.43 Da (62.11th percentile). For detailed sequence analysis methods, refer to <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython’s ProtParam documentation</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">yes</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="longest"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[AAAS description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ACACA</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ACACA/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ACACA"/><published>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ACACA</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ACACA/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/31">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">31</td> <td style="text-align: left">ACACA</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000278540</td> <td style="text-align: left">17q12</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene length is 1,161,878.0 base pairs (99.74% of all genes), the mature length is 3,464.5 base pairs, and the primary transcript length is 712,208.5 base pairs.</p> <p>The gene ACACA, with NCBI ID 31, has been the subject of <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22ACACA%22">292 publications</a> (count may differ as it is from <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>). The earliest year of publication is 1987, and the middle 50% of publications occurred between 2003 and 2019.</p> <p>The top 5 publications mentioning ACACA, ranked by their scientific influence, include: “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35363499">2022 AHA/ACC/HFSA Guideline for the Management of Heart Failure: A Report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Joint Committee on Clinical Practice Guidelines.</a> (2022) (relative citation ratio: 334.52),” “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35379503">2022 AHA/ACC/HFSA Guideline for the Management of Heart Failure: A Report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Joint Committee on Clinical Practice Guidelines.</a> (2022) (relative citation ratio: 139.72),” “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30586774">2018 AHA/ACC/AACVPR/AAPA/ABC/ACPM/ADA/AGS/APhA/ASPC/NLA/PCNA Guideline on the Management of Blood Cholesterol: A Report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Clinical Practice Guidelines.</a> (2019) (relative citation ratio: 131.97),” “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35363500">2022 AHA/ACC/HFSA Guideline for the Management of Heart Failure: Executive Summary: A Report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Joint Committee on Clinical Practice Guidelines.</a> (2022) (relative citation ratio: 55.1),” and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16160202">ACC/AHA 2005 Guideline Update for the Diagnosis and Management of Chronic Heart Failure in the Adult: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines (Writing Committee to Update the 2001 Guidelines for the Evaluation and Management of Heart Failure): developed in collaboration with the American College of Chest Physicians and the International Society for Heart and Lung Transplantation: endorsed by the Heart Rhythm Society.</a> (2005) (relative citation ratio: 54.55).” The <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">Relative Citation Ratio (RCR)</a> measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/1385">CREB1</a> and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/3725">JUN</a>, each with 6 experiments. Additionally, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/5460">POU5F1</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/4297">KMT2A</a>, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/4088">SMAD3</a> were each found to be regulating in 5 experiments.</p> <p>The analyzed protein sequence has a GRAVY value of -0.246 (64.33rd percentile), indicating a hydrophilic nature. The charge at pH 7.0 is -33.89 (5.08th percentile), and the median structural flexibility is 0.998 (30.28th percentile). The protein has a length of 2346 amino acids (98.38th percentile) and a molecular weight of 265550.74 Da (98.47th percentile). The secondary structure affinities are 30.31% for helix (34.74th percentile), 36.79% for sheet (71.65th percentile), and 27.66% for turn (44.26th percentile). The instability index is 41.32 (26.46th percentile), and the isoelectric point is 5.95 (29.32nd percentile). These calculations were performed using <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython’s sequence analysis tools</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">yes</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="longest"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACACA description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ACVR1</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ACVR1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ACVR1"/><published>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ACVR1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ACVR1/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/90">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">90</td> <td style="text-align: left">ACVR1</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000115170</td> <td style="text-align: left">2q24.1</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene length is 558,762.0 base pairs (98.68% of all genes), the mature length is 1,687.0 base pairs, and the primary transcript length is 532,346.5 base pairs.</p> <p>The gene ACVR1, with NCBI ID 90, has been the subject of <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22ACVR1%22">151 publications</a> (note: count may differ as it is sourced from <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>). The earliest year of publication is 1987, and the middle 50% of publications occurred between 2011 and 2020.</p> <p>The top five publications mentioning ACVR1, ranked by their scientific influence, include “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16642017">A recurrent mutation in the BMP type I receptor ACVR1 causes inherited and sporadic fibrodysplasia ossificans progressiva.</a>” (2006) with a <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">Relative Citation Ratio (RCR)</a> of 17.36, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24705254">Genomic analysis of diffuse intrinsic pontine gliomas identifies three molecular subgroups and recurrent activating ACVR1 mutations.</a>” (2014) with an RCR of 12.64, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24705252">Recurrent activating ACVR1 mutations in diffuse intrinsic pontine glioma.</a>” (2014) with an RCR of 9.9, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24705250">Recurrent somatic mutations in ACVR1 in pediatric midline high-grade astrocytoma.</a>” (2014) with an RCR of 8.5, and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26621707">Neofunction of ACVR1 in fibrodysplasia ossificans progressiva.</a>” (2015) with an RCR of 6.1. The Relative Citation Ratio (RCR) measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6829">SUPT5H</a> with 7 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/51341">ZBTB7A</a> with 5 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/5885">RAD21</a> with 5 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/4613">MYCN</a> with 5 experiments, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/4609">MYC</a> with 5 experiments. These TFs have been shown to play significant roles in gene regulation, as evidenced by their frequent appearance in CHIP-seq data.</p> <p>The mouse ortholog gene 11477, which corresponds to the human ortholog gene 90, is associated with several phenotypic outcomes. These include embryonic lethality prior to organogenesis and prior to the tooth bud stage, both specific to one sex. Additionally, the gene is linked to increased circulating total protein levels and complete penetrance preweaning lethality, both observed in both sexes.</p> <p>The analyzed protein sequence has a GRAVY value of -0.18015717092337935 (71.22nd percentile), indicating a relatively hydrophilic nature. The charge at pH 7.0 is 0.4008811927190763 (51.61st percentile), and the median structural flexibility is 0.9979047619047619 (31.83rd percentile). The protein has a length of 509 amino acids (59.4th percentile) and a molecular weight of 57152.2619000001 Da (59.75th percentile). The secondary structure affinities are 0.2829076620825147 for helix (18.82nd percentile), 0.3732809430255403 for sheet (74.95th percentile), and 0.2868369351669941 for turn (53.29th percentile). The instability index is 44.40591355599218 (37.17th percentile), and the isoelectric point is 7.117571830749512 (51.64th percentile). These values were calculated using <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython’s sequence analysis tools</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">yes</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="longest"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACVR1 description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">AIF1</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/AIF1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AIF1"/><published>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/AIF1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/AIF1/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/199">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">199</td> <td style="text-align: left">AIF1</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000204472</td> <td style="text-align: left">6p21.33</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene has a length of 566,190 base pairs (98.72% of all genes), a mature length of 8,308 base pairs, and a primary transcript length of 565,620 base pairs (99.43% of all genes).</p> <p>The gene AIF1 has an NCBI Gene ID of 199. It has been featured in <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22AIF1%22">136 publications</a> (note: count may differ as it is sourced from <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>). The earliest year of publication is 1996, and the middle 50% of publications occurred between 2007 and 2019.</p> <p>The top five publications mentioning AIF1, ranked by their scientific influence, include “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26470014">Sequential activation of microglia and astrocyte cytokine expression precedes increased Iba-1 or GFAP immunoreactivity following systemic immune challenge.</a>” (2016) (relative citation ratio: 15.41), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29547723">Metal Sensing by the IRT1 Transporter-Receptor Orchestrates Its Own Degradation and Plant Metal Nutrition.</a>” (2018) (relative citation ratio: 9.47), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35247551">Co-expression patterns of microglia markers Iba1, TMEM119 and P2RY12 in Alzheimer’s disease.</a>” (2022) (relative citation ratio: 8.07), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28601280">Staining of HLA-DR, Iba1 and CD68 in human microglia reveals partially overlapping expression depending on cellular morphology and pathology.</a>” (2017) (relative citation ratio: 6.86), and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10934045">Involvement of Iba1 in membrane ruffling and phagocytosis of macrophages/microglia.</a>” (2000) (relative citation ratio: 6.01). The relative citation ratio (<a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">RCR</a>) measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from GTRD’s database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/23476">BRD4</a> with 4 experiments, followed by <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/861">RUNX1</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2078">ERG</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2313">FLI1</a>, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/23028">KDM1A</a>, each with 3 experiments.</p> <p>Based on the data from GTRD’s database of transcription factor (TF) binding sites and filtered for Perturb-seq data, the top transcription factors in terms of the number of experiments showing their regulatory role are as follows: <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/23028">23028</a> with 3 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2623">2623</a> with 2 experiments, and both <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/4066">4066</a> and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/3190">3190</a> with 1 experiment each. These findings highlight the significant regulatory roles of these transcription factors in gene expression.</p> <p>AIF1 has been associated with variations in <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32888494">Mean platelet volume</a>, which maps closely to the MeSH term <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D063847">Mean Platelet Volume</a>. Additionally, it has been linked to <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32888494">Platelet count</a>, corresponding to the MeSH term <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D010976">Platelet Count</a>. These associations were identified using a method called <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-019-0055-0">BioWordVec</a>.</p> <p>The mouse ortholog gene 11629 and its human ortholog gene 199 are associated with abnormal optic disk morphology and decreased blood urea nitrogen levels, with these phenotypes observed in both sexes.</p> <p>The analyzed protein sequence has a GRAVY value of -0.699 (17.67th percentile), indicating a hydrophilic nature. The charge at pH 7.0 is -1.38 (45.15th percentile), and the median structural flexibility is 1.022 (97.62nd percentile). The protein has a high affinity for helix structures (0.463, 98.9th percentile), with lower affinities for sheet (0.286, 21.03rd percentile) and turn (0.299, 63.41st percentile) structures. The instability index is 52.45 (64.99th percentile), and the isoelectric point is 5.97 (29.83rd percentile). The protein is 147 amino acids long (7.7th percentile) with a molecular weight of 16703.13 Da (8.01st percentile). For more details on the sequence analysis, refer to <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython’s sequence analysis documentation</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">yes</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="longest"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[AIF1 description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ALDH5A1</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ALDH5A1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ALDH5A1"/><published>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ALDH5A1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ALDH5A1/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/7915">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">7915</td> <td style="text-align: left">ALDH5A1</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000112294</td> <td style="text-align: left">6p22.3</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene length is 453,373 base pairs (97.99% of all genes), the mature length is 5,169 base pairs, and the primary transcript length is 449,408 base pairs.</p> <p>The gene ALDH5A1, with NCBI ID 7915, has been the subject of <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22ALDH5A1%22">39 publications</a> (note: count may differ as it is sourced from <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>). The earliest year of publication is 1988, and the middle 50% of publications occurred between 2010 and 2017.</p> <p>The top five publications mentioning ALDH5A1, ranked by their scientific influence, include “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35269750">Understanding the Molecular Mechanisms of Succinic Semialdehyde Dehydrogenase Deficiency (SSADHD): Towards the Development of SSADH-Targeted Medicine.</a>” (2022) with a <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">Relative Citation Ratio (RCR)</a> of 2.77, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25485164">Disorders of GABA metabolism: SSADH and GABA-transaminase deficiencies.</a>” (2014) with an RCR of 2.08, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20973619">Succinic semialdehyde dehydrogenase: biochemical-molecular-clinical disease mechanisms, redox regulation, and functional significance.</a>” (2011) with an RCR of 1.87, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19300440">Redox-switch modulation of human SSADH by dynamic catalytic loop.</a>” (2009) with an RCR of 1.68, and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3190233">Human brain “high Km” aldehyde dehydrogenase: purification, characterization, and identification as NAD+ -dependent succinic semialdehyde dehydrogenase.</a>” (1988) with an RCR of 1.61. The Relative Citation Ratio (RCR) measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2099">ESR1</a> and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/23476">BRD4</a>, each with 5 experiments. Additionally, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/1025">CDK9</a> was found in 4 experiments, while <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6908">TBP</a> and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/1879">EBF1</a> were each identified in 3 experiments.</p> <p>The analyzed protein sequence has a GRAVY value of 0.010467289719626191 (84.43rd percentile), indicating a slight hydrophobicity. The charge at pH 7.0 is 7.037518520984591 (74.53rd percentile), and the median structural flexibility is 0.9977023809523811 (31.13rd percentile). The protein has a helix affinity of 0.34579439252336447 (72.09th percentile), a sheet affinity of 0.33644859813084105 (49.51st percentile), and a turn affinity of 0.2691588785046729 (37.24th percentile). The instability index is 39.01235514018689 (19.48th percentile), and the isoelectric point is 8.621437644958498 (69.28th percentile). The protein has a length of 535 amino acids (62.57th percentile) and a molecular weight of 57214.10820000011 Da (59.79th percentile). These calculations were performed using <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython’s sequence analysis tools</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">yes</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="longest"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ALDH5A1 description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ASAH1</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ASAH1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ASAH1"/><published>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ASAH1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ASAH1/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/427">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">427</td> <td style="text-align: left">ASAH1</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000104763</td> <td style="text-align: left">8p22</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene length is 53,931 base pairs (68.49% of all genes), the mature length is 1,342 base pairs, and the primary transcript length is 19,364 base pairs (50.81% of all genes).</p> <p>The gene ASAH1 (NCBI ID: 427) has been the subject of <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22ASAH1%22">150 publications</a> according to <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>, with the earliest publication dating back to 1980. The middle 50% of these publications were published between 2008 and 2019. Note that the publication count in the hyperlink may be different since the count is from Pubtator.</p> <p>The top five publications mentioning ASAH1, ranked by their scientific influence, include “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15655246">Molecular characterization of N-acylethanolamine-hydrolyzing acid amidase, a novel member of the choloylglycine hydrolase family with structural and functional similarity to acid ceramidase.</a>” (2005) (relative citation ratio: 6.19), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26898341">Lysosomal glycosphingolipid catabolism by acid ceramidase: formation of glycosphingoid bases during deficiency of glycosidases.</a>” (2016) (relative citation ratio: 4.39), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8955159">Molecular cloning and characterization of a full-length complementary DNA encoding human acid ceramidase. Identification Of the first molecular lesion causing Farber disease.</a>” (1996) (relative citation ratio: 4.25), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30029679">Acid ceramidase deficiency: Farber disease and SMA-PME.</a>” (2018) (relative citation ratio: 4.18), and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7744740">Purification, characterization, and biosynthesis of human acid ceramidase.</a>” (1995) (relative citation ratio: 4.05). The <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">Relative Citation Ratio (RCR)</a> measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/1385">CREB1</a> with 6 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/7528">YY1</a> with 5 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2099">ESR1</a> with 5 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/1024">CDK8</a> with 5 experiments, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/4297">KMT2A</a> with 5 experiments. These TFs have been shown to play significant roles in gene regulation, as evidenced by their frequent appearance in CHIP-seq data.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD database of TF binding sites, filtered for Perturb-seq data, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/5885">5885</a> with 5 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/9126">9126</a> with 4 experiments, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6829">6829</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2623">2623</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2118">2118</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/8243">8243</a>, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/9968">9968</a> each with 2 experiments. Additionally, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6830">6830</a> was found to be regulating in 1 experiment. These TFs were shown to significantly impact gene expression in the Perturb-seq experiments.</p> <p>The genome-wide association study has identified a link between the ASAH1 gene and <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35995766">Metabolite peak levels (QI3139)</a>.</p> <p>The analyzed protein sequence has a GRAVY value of -0.1111 (77.25th percentile), indicating a relatively hydrophilic nature. At pH 7.0, the protein carries a charge of 0.8973 (53.54th percentile). The median structural flexibility is 0.9960 (24.01st percentile), suggesting a fairly rigid structure. The protein has a length of 395 amino acids (44.6th percentile) and a molecular weight of 44659.12 Da (45.3rd percentile). The secondary structure affinities are 29.62% for helix (28.64th percentile), 42.53% for sheet (91.65th percentile), and 28.61% for turn (52.71st percentile). The instability index is 38.48 (18.08th percentile), and the isoelectric point is 7.52 (54.15th percentile). These calculations were performed using <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython’s sequence analysis tools</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">yes</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="replogle-least"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ASAH1 description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ATP6AP2</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ATP6AP2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ATP6AP2"/><published>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ATP6AP2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ATP6AP2/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/10159">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">10159</td> <td style="text-align: left">ATP6AP2</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000182220</td> <td style="text-align: left">Xp11.4</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene length is 91,425 base pairs (80.22% of all genes), the mature length is 1,131 base pairs (26.85% of all genes), and the primary transcript length is 59,470 base pairs (79.17% of all genes).</p> <p>The gene ATP6AP2, with NCBI ID 10159, has been featured in <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22ATP6AP2%22">258 publications</a> (note: count may differ as it is sourced from <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>). The earliest year of publication is 1998, and the middle 50% of publications occurred between 2010 and 2019.</p> <p>The top five publications mentioning ATP6AP2, ranked by their scientific influence, include “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12045255">Pivotal role of the renin/prorenin receptor in angiotensin II production and cellular responses to renin.</a>” (2002) with a <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">Relative Citation Ratio (RCR)</a> of 23.4, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18490518">Effects of aliskiren on blood pressure, albuminuria, and (pro)renin receptor expression in diabetic TG(mRen-2)27 rats.</a>” (2008) with an RCR of 6.62, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17082479">A novel signal transduction cascade involving direct physical interaction of the renin/prorenin receptor with the transcription factor promyelocytic zinc finger protein.</a>” (2006) with an RCR of 5.67, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17494887">Slowly progressive, angiotensin II-independent glomerulosclerosis in human (pro)renin receptor-transgenic rats.</a>” (2007) with an RCR of 5.3, and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17984666">Prorenin is the endogenous agonist of the (pro)renin receptor. Binding kinetics of renin and prorenin in rat vascular smooth muscle cells overexpressing the human (pro)renin receptor.</a>” (2007) with an RCR of 4.56. The Relative Citation Ratio (RCR) measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/5241">PGR</a> and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2078">ERG</a>, each with 5 experiments. Additionally, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/3169">FOXA1</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6688">SPI1</a>, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/8930">MBD4</a> were each found to be regulating in 4 experiments.</p> <p>Based on the data from GTRD’s database of transcription factor (TF) binding sites and filtered for Perturb-seq data, several transcription factors were identified as significant regulators in multiple experiments. Notably, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/9126">TFAP2A</a> was found to regulate gene expression in three experiments. Additionally, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6829">NFE2L2</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2623">GATA1</a>, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/9968">HIF1A</a> each showed regulatory activity in two experiments. These findings highlight the critical roles of these transcription factors in gene regulation.</p> <p>The analyzed protein sequence has a GRAVY value of 0.104 (88.09th percentile), indicating a relatively hydrophobic nature. The charge at pH 7.0 is -4.93 (33.96th percentile), and the median structural flexibility is 0.997 (28.07th percentile). The protein has a predicted secondary structure with 33.43% helix (63.12th percentile), 40.00% sheet (86.16th percentile), and 31.14% turn (71.49th percentile) affinities. The instability index is 37.08 (14.4th percentile), and the isoelectric point is 5.76 (24.32nd percentile). The protein is 350 amino acids long (38.03rd percentile) with a molecular weight of 39007.53 Da (38.0th percentile). For more details on the sequence analysis, refer to the <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython documentation</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">yes</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="replogle-least"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ATP6AP2 description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">B2M</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/B2M/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="B2M"/><published>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/B2M</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/B2M/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/567">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">567</td> <td style="text-align: left">B2M</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000166710</td> <td style="text-align: left">15q21.1</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene length is 62,091 base pairs (71.74th percentile), the mature length is 1,822 base pairs (47.83rd percentile), and the primary transcript length is 60,215 base pairs (79.43rd percentile).</p> <p>The gene B2M (NCBI ID: 567) has been the subject of <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22B2M%22">2,987 publications</a> according to <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>, with the earliest publication dating back to 1964. The middle 50% of these publications were published between 1986 and 2005.</p> <p>The top five publications mentioning B2M, ranked by their scientific influence, include “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3893430">A new form of amyloid protein associated with chronic hemodialysis was identified as beta 2-microglobulin.</a>” (1985) (relative citation ratio: 28.01), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/84336">Effect of control of blood glucose on urinary excretion of albumin and beta2 microglobulin in insulin-dependent diabetes.</a>” (1979) (relative citation ratio: 23.65), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8770866">Normal luminal bacteria, especially Bacteroides species, mediate chronic colitis, gastritis, and arthritis in HLA-B27/human beta2 microglobulin transgenic rats.</a>” (1996) (relative citation ratio: 15.25), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8376584">beta 2-Microglobulin modified with advanced glycation end products is a major component of hemodialysis-associated amyloidosis.</a>” (1993) (relative citation ratio: 11.58), and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2881162">No change in corrected beta 2-microglobulin concentration after cuprophane haemodialysis.</a>” (1987) (relative citation ratio: 10.56). The <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">Relative Citation Ratio (RCR)</a> measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD’s database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2908">NR3C1</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/10664">CTCF</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2033">EP300</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6667">SP1</a>, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/84678">KDM2B</a>, each shown to be regulating in 5 experiments.</p> <p>Based on the data from GTRD’s database of transcription factor (TF) binding sites and filtered for Perturb-seq data, several TFs were identified as significant regulators in multiple experiments. Notably, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6829">STAT1</a> and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2623">IRF1</a> were each found to regulate gene expression in 2 experiments. <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/23028">ZNF274</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6872">KLF10</a>, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/9968">HIVEP1</a> were identified in 3 experiments each. Additionally, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/8243">ZNF384</a> was found in 2 experiments, while <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6426">ZNF629</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6749">ZNF783</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6830">ZNF787</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/8861">ZNF804A</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/57634">ZNF845</a>, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/9126">ZNF879</a> were each identified in 1 experiment.</p> <p>The mouse ortholog gene 12010 and its human ortholog gene 567 are associated with several phenotypes. Both sexes exhibit abnormal skin morphology, preweaning lethality with complete penetrance, and preweaning lethality with incomplete penetrance. Additionally, female mice show embryonic lethality prior to the tooth bud stage, hydrometra, and a small superior vagus ganglion.</p> <p>The analyzed protein sequence has a GRAVY value of -0.376 (48.99th percentile), indicating a hydrophilic nature. At pH 7.0, the protein carries a charge of -2.15 (42.59th percentile). The median structural flexibility is 0.997 (27.64th percentile). The protein’s secondary structure tends to be 31.93% helix (49.72nd percentile) and 37.82% sheet (77.52nd percentile), with 28.57% turn (52.36th percentile). The instability index is 33.82 (8.25th percentile), and the isoelectric point is 6.06 (32.01st percentile). The protein is 119 amino acids long (4.59th percentile) with a molecular weight of 13714.4 Da (4.98th percentile). For more details on the sequence analysis, refer to <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython’s ProtParam documentation</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">yes</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="replogle-least"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[B2M description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">BSG</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/BSG/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BSG"/><published>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/BSG</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/BSG/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/682">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">682</td> <td style="text-align: left">BSG</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000172270</td> <td style="text-align: left">19p13.3</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene length is 56,506 base pairs (69.57% of all genes), the mature length is 989 base pairs (22.11% of all genes), and the primary transcript length is 50,790 base pairs (75.66% of all genes).</p> <p>The gene BSG (NCBI ID: 682) has been the subject of <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22BSG%22">821 publications</a> (count from <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>, may differ from the hyperlink count). The earliest year of publication is 1988, and the middle 50% of publications occurred between 2009 and 2018.</p> <p>The top 5 publications mentioning BSG, also known as CD147, include “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33277466">CD147-spike protein is a novel route for SARS-CoV-2 infection to host cells.</a>” (2020) with a relative citation ratio of 56.75, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32496587">Distribution of ACE2, CD147, CD26, and other SARS-CoV-2 associated molecules in tissues and immune cells in health and in asthma, COPD, obesity, hypertension, and COVID-19 risk factors.</a>” (2020) with a relative citation ratio of 25.64, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32307653">CD147 as a Target for COVID-19 Treatment: Suggested Effects of Azithromycin and Stem Cell Engagement.</a>” (2020) with a relative citation ratio of 22.67, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35109786">The roles of Eph receptors, neuropilin-1, P2X7, and CD147 in COVID-19-associated neurodegenerative diseases: inflammasome and JaK inhibitors as potential promising therapies.</a>” (2022) with a relative citation ratio of 11.05, and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34863742">CD147-spike protein interaction in COVID-19: Get the ball rolling with a novel receptor and therapeutic target.</a>” (2022) with a relative citation ratio of 11.0. The <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">Relative Citation Ratio (RCR)</a> measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from GTRD’s database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2908">NR3C1</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2033">EP300</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6599">SMARCC1</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2078">ERG</a>, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/4609">MYC</a>, each shown to be regulating in 5 experiments.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD database of TF binding sites, filtered for Perturb-seq data, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6829">CTCF</a> with 3 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/11091">ZNF274</a> with 2 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/9968">ZNF263</a> with 2 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/55929">ZNF592</a> with 2 experiments, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/9126">ZNF559</a> with 2 experiments. These TFs were found to regulate gene expression in multiple Perturb-seq experiments, highlighting their significant roles in transcriptional regulation.</p> <p>A recent genome-wide association study has identified significant associations with <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28714976">Alzheimer’s disease (late onset)</a>, which was mapped to the closest MeSH term <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D004194">Disease</a> using the <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-019-0055-0">BioWordVec</a> method. Additionally, the study found associations with <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28881265">Endometriosis</a>, which directly matched the MeSH term <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D004715">Endometriosis</a>.</p> <p>The analyzed protein sequence has a GRAVY value of -0.323 (55.32nd percentile), indicating a hydrophilic nature. The charge at pH 7.0 is -13.36 (17.42nd percentile), and the median structural flexibility is 1.003 (55.58th percentile). The protein has a predicted secondary structure with 29.35% helix (26.22nd percentile), 34.03% sheet (52.21st percentile), and 30.91% turn (69.97th percentile) affinities. The instability index is 41.02 (25.38th percentile), and the isoelectric point is 5.39 (15.69th percentile). The protein is 385 amino acids long (43.24th percentile) with a molecular weight of 42199.87 Da (42.41st percentile). For more details on sequence analysis, refer to <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython’s sequence analysis documentation</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">yes</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="replogle-least"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[BSG description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">BTG2</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/BTG2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BTG2"/><published>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/BTG2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/BTG2/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/7832">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">7832</td> <td style="text-align: left">BTG2</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000159388</td> <td style="text-align: left">1q32.1</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene length is 50,172.0 base pairs (66.43% of all genes), the mature length is 1,211.5 base pairs, and the primary transcript length is 36,761.0 base pairs.</p> <p>The gene BTG2 (NCBI ID: 7832) has been the subject of <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22BTG2%22">139 publications</a> (count from <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>, may differ from the hyperlink). The earliest year of publication is 1995, and the middle 50% of publications occurred between 2010 and 2020.</p> <p>The top five publications mentioning BTG2, ranked by their scientific influence, include “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8663146">The mammalian immediate-early TIS21 protein and the leukemia-associated BTG1 protein interact with a protein-arginine N-methyltransferase.</a>” (1996) with a <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">Relative Citation Ratio (RCR)</a> of 7.04, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8944033">Identification of BTG2, an antiproliferative p53-dependent component of the DNA damage cellular response pathway.</a>” (1996) with an RCR of 6.53, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30350856">Tumor suppressors BTG1 and BTG2: Beyond growth control.</a>” (2019) with an RCR of 6.23, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31924214">TEAD4 modulated LncRNA MNX1-AS1 contributes to gastric cancer progression partly through suppressing BTG2 and activating BCL2.</a>” (2020) with an RCR of 5.48, and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22266859">Androgen-regulated miR-32 targets BTG2 and is overexpressed in castration-resistant prostate cancer.</a>” (2012) with an RCR of 4.77. The Relative Citation Ratio (RCR) measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/861">RUNX1</a> with 6 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2033">EP300</a> with 5 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/5914">RARA</a> with 5 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/4149">MAX</a> with 5 experiments, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/65980">BRD9</a> with 5 experiments. These TFs have been shown to play significant roles in gene regulation, as evidenced by their frequent appearance in CHIP-seq data.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD’s database of TF binding sites, filtered for Perturb-seq data, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6829">6829</a> and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/9126">9126</a>, each shown to be regulating genes in 3 experiments. Additionally, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/8243">8243</a> was found to regulate genes in 2 experiments. Other notable TFs include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/65123">65123</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/8861">8861</a>, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/9968">9968</a>, each shown to regulate genes in 1 experiment.</p> <p>The gene BTG2 has been associated with <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34226706">Mean reticulocyte volume</a>, which maps closely to the MeSH term <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D012156">Reticulocytes</a> using the <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-019-0055-0">BioWordVec</a> method.</p> <p>The mouse ortholog gene 12227 and its human ortholog 7832 are associated with several phenotypes. Notably, the mouse model exhibits an enlarged uterus, a phenotype observed only in females. Additionally, both sexes display increased fasting circulating glucose levels, increased mean corpuscular hemoglobin, and increased mean corpuscular volume. These findings highlight the potential relevance of these orthologs in understanding corresponding human conditions.</p> <p>The analyzed protein sequence has a GRAVY value of -0.134 (75.37th percentile), indicating a relatively hydrophilic nature. The charge at pH 7.0 is 1.992 (57.52nd percentile), and the median structural flexibility is 0.996 (23.17th percentile). The protein has a propensity for helix, sheet, and turn structures of 32.28% (53.07th percentile), 33.54% (48.82nd percentile), and 29.75% (61.95th percentile), respectively. The instability index is 49.19 (54.54th percentile), and the isoelectric point is 8.29 (62.62nd percentile). The protein is 158 amino acids long (9.01st percentile) with a molecular weight of 17415.88 Da (8.76th percentile). For more details on the sequence analysis, refer to the <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython documentation</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">yes</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="replogle-least"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[BTG2 description]]></summary></entry></feed>