<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-12-09T13:00:22+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A data-driven literature for understudied genes. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">AAAS</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/AAAS/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AAAS"/><published>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/AAAS</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/AAAS/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/8086">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">8086</td> <td style="text-align: left">AAAS</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000094914</td> <td style="text-align: left">12q13.13</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene length is 878,010 base pairs (99.45% of all genes), the mature length is 4,948.5 base pairs, and the primary transcript length is 573,840 base pairs (99.46% of all genes).</p> <p>The gene AAAS, with NCBI ID 8086, has been the subject of <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22AAAS%22">94 publications</a> (note: count may differ as it is sourced from <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>). The earliest year of publication is 1948, and the middle 50% of publications occurred between 1986 and 2010.</p> <p>The top five publications mentioning the AAAS gene, ranked by their scientific influence, include “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11159947">Triple A syndrome is caused by mutations in AAAS, a new WD-repeat protein gene.</a>” (2001) with a <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">Relative Citation Ratio (RCR)</a> of 3.43, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12730363">The nuclear pore complex protein ALADIN is mislocalized in triple A syndrome.</a>” (2003) with an RCR of 2.16, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16609705">Cellular localization of 17 natural mutant variants of ALADIN protein in triple A syndrome - shedding light on an unexpected splice mutation.</a>” (2006) with an RCR of 1.2, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11701718">Spectrum of mutations of the AAAS gene in Allgrove syndrome: lack of mutations in six kindreds with isolated resistance to corticotropin.</a>” (2001) with an RCR of 1.14, and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26246606">The nucleoporin ALADIN regulates Aurora A localization to ensure robust mitotic spindle formation.</a>” (2015) with an RCR of 1.13. The Relative Citation Ratio (RCR) measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD database, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/5970">RELA</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/5978">REST</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/1876">E2F6</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/5241">PGR</a>, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/7227">TRPS1</a>, each shown to be regulating in 5 experiments.</p> <p>The analyzed protein sequence has a GRAVY value of -0.084 (79.18th percentile), indicating a hydrophilic nature. At pH 7.0, the protein carries a charge of 0.995 (53.96th percentile). The median structural flexibility is 0.997 (26.57th percentile), with a secondary structure composition of 26.2% helix (8.38th percentile), 36.8% sheet (71.81st percentile), and 33.5% turn (84.14th percentile). The instability index is 43.73 (34.71st percentile), and the isoelectric point is 7.26 (52.82nd percentile). The protein is 546 amino acids long (63.7th percentile) with a molecular weight of 59573.43 Da (62.11th percentile). For detailed sequence analysis methods, refer to <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython’s ProtParam documentation</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">yes</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="longest"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[AAAS description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ACACA</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ACACA/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ACACA"/><published>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ACACA</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ACACA/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/31">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">31</td> <td style="text-align: left">ACACA</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000278540</td> <td style="text-align: left">17q12</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene length is 1,161,878.0 base pairs (99.74% of all genes), the mature length is 3,464.5 base pairs, and the primary transcript length is 712,208.5 base pairs.</p> <p>The gene ACACA, with NCBI ID 31, has been the subject of <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22ACACA%22">292 publications</a> (count may differ as it is from <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>). The earliest year of publication is 1987, and the middle 50% of publications occurred between 2003 and 2019.</p> <p>The top 5 publications mentioning ACACA, ranked by their scientific influence, include: “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35363499">2022 AHA/ACC/HFSA Guideline for the Management of Heart Failure: A Report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Joint Committee on Clinical Practice Guidelines.</a> (2022) (relative citation ratio: 334.52),” “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35379503">2022 AHA/ACC/HFSA Guideline for the Management of Heart Failure: A Report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Joint Committee on Clinical Practice Guidelines.</a> (2022) (relative citation ratio: 139.72),” “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30586774">2018 AHA/ACC/AACVPR/AAPA/ABC/ACPM/ADA/AGS/APhA/ASPC/NLA/PCNA Guideline on the Management of Blood Cholesterol: A Report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Clinical Practice Guidelines.</a> (2019) (relative citation ratio: 131.97),” “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35363500">2022 AHA/ACC/HFSA Guideline for the Management of Heart Failure: Executive Summary: A Report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Joint Committee on Clinical Practice Guidelines.</a> (2022) (relative citation ratio: 55.1),” and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16160202">ACC/AHA 2005 Guideline Update for the Diagnosis and Management of Chronic Heart Failure in the Adult: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines (Writing Committee to Update the 2001 Guidelines for the Evaluation and Management of Heart Failure): developed in collaboration with the American College of Chest Physicians and the International Society for Heart and Lung Transplantation: endorsed by the Heart Rhythm Society.</a> (2005) (relative citation ratio: 54.55).” The <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">Relative Citation Ratio (RCR)</a> measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/1385">CREB1</a> and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/3725">JUN</a>, each with 6 experiments. Additionally, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/5460">POU5F1</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/4297">KMT2A</a>, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/4088">SMAD3</a> were each found to be regulating in 5 experiments.</p> <p>The analyzed protein sequence has a GRAVY value of -0.246 (64.33rd percentile), indicating a hydrophilic nature. The charge at pH 7.0 is -33.89 (5.08th percentile), and the median structural flexibility is 0.998 (30.28th percentile). The protein has a length of 2346 amino acids (98.38th percentile) and a molecular weight of 265550.74 Da (98.47th percentile). The secondary structure affinities are 30.31% for helix (34.74th percentile), 36.79% for sheet (71.65th percentile), and 27.66% for turn (44.26th percentile). The instability index is 41.32 (26.46th percentile), and the isoelectric point is 5.95 (29.32nd percentile). These calculations were performed using <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython’s sequence analysis tools</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">yes</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="longest"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACACA description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ACVR1</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ACVR1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ACVR1"/><published>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ACVR1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ACVR1/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/90">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">90</td> <td style="text-align: left">ACVR1</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000115170</td> <td style="text-align: left">2q24.1</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene length is 558,762.0 base pairs (98.68% of all genes), the mature length is 1,687.0 base pairs, and the primary transcript length is 532,346.5 base pairs.</p> <p>The gene ACVR1, with NCBI ID 90, has been the subject of <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22ACVR1%22">151 publications</a> (note: count may differ as it is sourced from <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>). The earliest year of publication is 1987, and the middle 50% of publications occurred between 2011 and 2020.</p> <p>The top five publications mentioning ACVR1, ranked by their scientific influence, include “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16642017">A recurrent mutation in the BMP type I receptor ACVR1 causes inherited and sporadic fibrodysplasia ossificans progressiva.</a>” (2006) with a <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">Relative Citation Ratio (RCR)</a> of 17.36, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24705254">Genomic analysis of diffuse intrinsic pontine gliomas identifies three molecular subgroups and recurrent activating ACVR1 mutations.</a>” (2014) with an RCR of 12.64, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24705252">Recurrent activating ACVR1 mutations in diffuse intrinsic pontine glioma.</a>” (2014) with an RCR of 9.9, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24705250">Recurrent somatic mutations in ACVR1 in pediatric midline high-grade astrocytoma.</a>” (2014) with an RCR of 8.5, and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26621707">Neofunction of ACVR1 in fibrodysplasia ossificans progressiva.</a>” (2015) with an RCR of 6.1. The Relative Citation Ratio (RCR) measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6829">SUPT5H</a> with 7 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/51341">ZBTB7A</a> with 5 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/5885">RAD21</a> with 5 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/4613">MYCN</a> with 5 experiments, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/4609">MYC</a> with 5 experiments. These TFs have been shown to play significant roles in gene regulation, as evidenced by their frequent appearance in CHIP-seq data.</p> <p>The mouse ortholog gene 11477, which corresponds to the human ortholog gene 90, is associated with several phenotypic outcomes. These include embryonic lethality prior to organogenesis and prior to the tooth bud stage, both specific to one sex. Additionally, the gene is linked to increased circulating total protein levels and complete penetrance preweaning lethality, both observed in both sexes.</p> <p>The analyzed protein sequence has a GRAVY value of -0.18015717092337935 (71.22nd percentile), indicating a relatively hydrophilic nature. The charge at pH 7.0 is 0.4008811927190763 (51.61st percentile), and the median structural flexibility is 0.9979047619047619 (31.83rd percentile). The protein has a length of 509 amino acids (59.4th percentile) and a molecular weight of 57152.2619000001 Da (59.75th percentile). The secondary structure affinities are 0.2829076620825147 for helix (18.82nd percentile), 0.3732809430255403 for sheet (74.95th percentile), and 0.2868369351669941 for turn (53.29th percentile). The instability index is 44.40591355599218 (37.17th percentile), and the isoelectric point is 7.117571830749512 (51.64th percentile). These values were calculated using <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython’s sequence analysis tools</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">yes</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="longest"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACVR1 description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">AIF1</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/AIF1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AIF1"/><published>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/AIF1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/AIF1/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/199">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">199</td> <td style="text-align: left">AIF1</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000204472</td> <td style="text-align: left">6p21.33</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene has a length of 566,190 base pairs (98.72% of all genes), a mature length of 8,308 base pairs, and a primary transcript length of 565,620 base pairs (99.43% of all genes).</p> <p>The gene AIF1 has an NCBI Gene ID of 199. It has been featured in <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22AIF1%22">136 publications</a> (note: count may differ as it is sourced from <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>). The earliest year of publication is 1996, and the middle 50% of publications occurred between 2007 and 2019.</p> <p>The top five publications mentioning AIF1, ranked by their scientific influence, include “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26470014">Sequential activation of microglia and astrocyte cytokine expression precedes increased Iba-1 or GFAP immunoreactivity following systemic immune challenge.</a>” (2016) (relative citation ratio: 15.41), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29547723">Metal Sensing by the IRT1 Transporter-Receptor Orchestrates Its Own Degradation and Plant Metal Nutrition.</a>” (2018) (relative citation ratio: 9.47), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35247551">Co-expression patterns of microglia markers Iba1, TMEM119 and P2RY12 in Alzheimer’s disease.</a>” (2022) (relative citation ratio: 8.07), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28601280">Staining of HLA-DR, Iba1 and CD68 in human microglia reveals partially overlapping expression depending on cellular morphology and pathology.</a>” (2017) (relative citation ratio: 6.86), and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10934045">Involvement of Iba1 in membrane ruffling and phagocytosis of macrophages/microglia.</a>” (2000) (relative citation ratio: 6.01). The relative citation ratio (<a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">RCR</a>) measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from GTRD’s database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/23476">BRD4</a> with 4 experiments, followed by <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/861">RUNX1</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2078">ERG</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2313">FLI1</a>, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/23028">KDM1A</a>, each with 3 experiments.</p> <p>Based on the data from GTRD’s database of transcription factor (TF) binding sites and filtered for Perturb-seq data, the top transcription factors in terms of the number of experiments showing their regulatory role are as follows: <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/23028">23028</a> with 3 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2623">2623</a> with 2 experiments, and both <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/4066">4066</a> and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/3190">3190</a> with 1 experiment each. These findings highlight the significant regulatory roles of these transcription factors in gene expression.</p> <p>AIF1 has been associated with variations in <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32888494">Mean platelet volume</a>, which maps closely to the MeSH term <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D063847">Mean Platelet Volume</a>. Additionally, it has been linked to <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32888494">Platelet count</a>, corresponding to the MeSH term <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D010976">Platelet Count</a>. These associations were identified using a method called <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-019-0055-0">BioWordVec</a>.</p> <p>The mouse ortholog gene 11629 and its human ortholog gene 199 are associated with abnormal optic disk morphology and decreased blood urea nitrogen levels, with these phenotypes observed in both sexes.</p> <p>The analyzed protein sequence has a GRAVY value of -0.699 (17.67th percentile), indicating a hydrophilic nature. The charge at pH 7.0 is -1.38 (45.15th percentile), and the median structural flexibility is 1.022 (97.62nd percentile). The protein has a high affinity for helix structures (0.463, 98.9th percentile), with lower affinities for sheet (0.286, 21.03rd percentile) and turn (0.299, 63.41st percentile) structures. The instability index is 52.45 (64.99th percentile), and the isoelectric point is 5.97 (29.83rd percentile). The protein is 147 amino acids long (7.7th percentile) with a molecular weight of 16703.13 Da (8.01st percentile). For more details on the sequence analysis, refer to <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython’s sequence analysis documentation</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">yes</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="longest"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[AIF1 description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ALDH5A1</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ALDH5A1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ALDH5A1"/><published>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ALDH5A1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ALDH5A1/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/7915">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">7915</td> <td style="text-align: left">ALDH5A1</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000112294</td> <td style="text-align: left">6p22.3</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene length is 453,373 base pairs (97.99% of all genes), the mature length is 5,169 base pairs, and the primary transcript length is 449,408 base pairs.</p> <p>The gene ALDH5A1, with NCBI ID 7915, has been the subject of <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22ALDH5A1%22">39 publications</a> (note: count may differ as it is sourced from <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>). The earliest year of publication is 1988, and the middle 50% of publications occurred between 2010 and 2017.</p> <p>The top five publications mentioning ALDH5A1, ranked by their scientific influence, include “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35269750">Understanding the Molecular Mechanisms of Succinic Semialdehyde Dehydrogenase Deficiency (SSADHD): Towards the Development of SSADH-Targeted Medicine.</a>” (2022) with a <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">Relative Citation Ratio (RCR)</a> of 2.77, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25485164">Disorders of GABA metabolism: SSADH and GABA-transaminase deficiencies.</a>” (2014) with an RCR of 2.08, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20973619">Succinic semialdehyde dehydrogenase: biochemical-molecular-clinical disease mechanisms, redox regulation, and functional significance.</a>” (2011) with an RCR of 1.87, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19300440">Redox-switch modulation of human SSADH by dynamic catalytic loop.</a>” (2009) with an RCR of 1.68, and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3190233">Human brain “high Km” aldehyde dehydrogenase: purification, characterization, and identification as NAD+ -dependent succinic semialdehyde dehydrogenase.</a>” (1988) with an RCR of 1.61. The Relative Citation Ratio (RCR) measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2099">ESR1</a> and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/23476">BRD4</a>, each with 5 experiments. Additionally, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/1025">CDK9</a> was found in 4 experiments, while <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6908">TBP</a> and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/1879">EBF1</a> were each identified in 3 experiments.</p> <p>The analyzed protein sequence has a GRAVY value of 0.010467289719626191 (84.43rd percentile), indicating a slight hydrophobicity. The charge at pH 7.0 is 7.037518520984591 (74.53rd percentile), and the median structural flexibility is 0.9977023809523811 (31.13rd percentile). The protein has a helix affinity of 0.34579439252336447 (72.09th percentile), a sheet affinity of 0.33644859813084105 (49.51st percentile), and a turn affinity of 0.2691588785046729 (37.24th percentile). The instability index is 39.01235514018689 (19.48th percentile), and the isoelectric point is 8.621437644958498 (69.28th percentile). The protein has a length of 535 amino acids (62.57th percentile) and a molecular weight of 57214.10820000011 Da (59.79th percentile). These calculations were performed using <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython’s sequence analysis tools</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">yes</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="longest"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ALDH5A1 description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">C2CD2L</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/C2CD2L/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="C2CD2L"/><published>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/C2CD2L</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/C2CD2L/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/9854">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">9854</td> <td style="text-align: left">C2CD2L</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000172375</td> <td style="text-align: left">11q23.3</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene length is 653,878 base pairs (99.03% of all genes), the mature length is 8,756 base pairs (98.36% of all genes), and the primary transcript length is 652,899 base pairs (99.6% of all genes).</p> <p>The gene C2CD2L, with NCBI ID 9854, has been featured in <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22C2CD2L%22">4 publications</a> (count may differ as it is sourced from <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>). The earliest year of publication is 2004, and the middle 50% of publications occurred between 2010 and 2018.</p> <p>The top publications mentioning C2CD2L, ranked by their scientific influence as measured by the <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">Relative Citation Ratio (RCR)</a>, include “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28209843">Lipid transport by TMEM24 at ER-plasma membrane contacts regulates pulsatile insulin secretion.</a>” (2017) with an RCR of 4.77, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24012759">Insulin biosynthetic interaction network component, TMEM24, facilitates insulin reserve pool release.</a>” (2013) with an RCR of 0.79, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34821358">The endoplasmic reticulum-plasma membrane tethering protein TMEM24 is a regulator of cellular Ca2+ homeostasis.</a>” (2022) with an RCR of 0.45, and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15289880">Identification and characterization of TMEM24 family genes in silico.</a>” (2004) with an RCR of 0.14. The RCR values measure the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6772">STAT1</a> with 6 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/4800">NFYA</a> with 5 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/25942">SIN3A</a> with 5 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/1024">CDK8</a> with 5 experiments, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/7157">TP53</a> with 5 experiments. These TFs have been shown to play significant roles in gene regulation, as evidenced by their frequent appearance in CHIP-seq data.</p> <p>The mouse ortholog gene 71764 and its human ortholog gene 9854 are associated with the phenotype ‘abnormal auditory brainstem response’. This phenotype was observed in a sex-specific manner.</p> <p>The analyzed protein sequence has a GRAVY value of -0.4001 (46.1% percentile), indicating a hydrophilic nature. The charge at pH 7.0 is 1.3500 (55.07% percentile), and the median structural flexibility is 1.0098 (80.7% percentile). The protein has a high instability index of 58.82 (80.8% percentile) and an isoelectric point of 7.61 (55.32% percentile). The sequence length is 706 amino acids (75.64% percentile) with a molecular weight of 76180.39 Da (74.27% percentile). The secondary structure affinities are 0.3244 for helix (54.51% percentile), 0.3144 for sheet (36.38% percentile), and 0.3300 for turn (81.97% percentile). These calculations were performed using <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython’s sequence analysis tools</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">yes</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="longest"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[C2CD2L description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">C4A</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/C4A/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="C4A"/><published>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/C4A</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/C4A/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/720">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">720</td> <td style="text-align: left">C4A</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000244731</td> <td style="text-align: left">6p21.33</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene length is 1,102,672.0 base pairs (99.67% of all genes), the mature length is 4,160.0 base pairs, and the primary transcript length is 1,102,669.0 base pairs.</p> <p>The gene C4A, with NCBI ID 720, has been the subject of <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22C4A%22">243 publications</a> (note: count may differ as it is sourced from <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>). The earliest year of publication is 1970, and the middle 50% of publications occurred between 1988 and 2010.</p> <p>The top five publications mentioning C4A, ranked by their scientific influence as measured by the <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">Relative Citation Ratio (RCR)</a>, include “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33353966">Overexpression of schizophrenia susceptibility factor human complement C4A promotes excessive synaptic loss and behavioral changes in mice.</a>” (2021) (relative citation ratio: 13.61), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/6278136">Leukotrienes C4, D4 and E4: effects on human and guinea-pig cardiac preparations in vitro.</a>” (1982) (relative citation ratio: 8.4), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/6332733">A comparison of the properties of two classes, C4A and C4B, of the human complement component C4.</a>” (1984) (relative citation ratio: 6.94), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23383423">International Union of Basic and Clinical Pharmacology. [corrected]. LXXXVII. Complement peptide C5a, C4a, and C3a receptors.</a>” (2013) (relative citation ratio: 5.62), and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15725003">Steric and electronic properties of N-heterocyclic carbenes (NHC): a detailed study on their interaction with Ni(CO)4.</a>” (2005) (relative citation ratio: 5.61). The RCR values measure the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p>The gene <a href="https://www.proteinatlas.org/[Ensembl]-[Gene]">Blood group antigen</a> functions as a blood group antigen and is implicated in systemic lupus erythematosus, with evidence at the protein level. It is detected in many tissues and is particularly expressed in the liver, where it plays a role in metabolism. In the brain, it is found in astrocytes with mixed functions. The gene is also expressed in the DU4475 cell line and hepatocytes, where it is involved in metabolism.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from GTRD’s database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/3169">FOXA1</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6015">RING1</a>, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6773">STAT2</a>, each shown to be regulating in 2 experiments. Additionally, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/23543">RBFOX2</a> and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/1789">DNMT3B</a> were each found to be regulating in 1 experiment.</p> <p>The analyzed protein sequence has a GRAVY value of -0.252 (63.59th percentile), indicating a hydrophilic nature. The charge at pH 7.0 is -4.202 (35.82nd percentile), and the median structural flexibility is 1.000 (42.19th percentile). The protein has a propensity for helix, sheet, and turn structures of 31.48% (45.55th percentile), 35.32% (61.46th percentile), and 29.30% (58.36th percentile), respectively. The instability index is 45.814 (42.21st percentile), with an isoelectric point of 6.655 (45.5th percentile). The sequence length is 1744 amino acids (96.48th percentile), and the molecular weight is 192783.18 Da (96.39th percentile). For more details on the sequence analysis, refer to the <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython documentation</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">yes</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="longest"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[C4A description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">C4B</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/C4B/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="C4B"/><published>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/C4B</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/C4B/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/721">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">721</td> <td style="text-align: left">C4B</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000224389</td> <td style="text-align: left">6p21.33</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene length is 1,173,676.0 base pairs (99.76% of all genes), the mature length is 1,825.5 base pairs, and the primary transcript length is 861,116.5 base pairs (99.82% of all genes).</p> <p>The gene C4B, with NCBI ID 721, has been the subject of <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22C4B%22">203 publications</a> (note: count may differ as it is sourced from <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>). The earliest year of publication is 1975, and the middle 50% of publications occurred between 1988 and 2005.</p> <p>The top five publications mentioning C4B, ranked by their scientific influence, include “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/6401549">Family study of the major histocompatibility complex in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: importance of null alleles of C4A and C4B in determining disease susceptibility</a>” (1983) (relative citation ratio: 10.44), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/702059">Human C4-binding protein. II. Role in proteolysis of C4b by C3b-inactivator</a>” (1978) (relative citation ratio: 9.22), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25290405">Complement system proteins which interact with C3b or C4b A superfamily of structurally related proteins</a>” (1986) (relative citation ratio: 6.27), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/6222381">Visualization of human C4b-binding protein and its complexes with vitamin K-dependent protein S and complement protein C4b</a>” (1983) (relative citation ratio: 5.26), and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35648811">Targeting C3b/C4b and VEGF with a bispecific fusion protein optimized for neovascular age-related macular degeneration therapy</a>” (2022) (relative citation ratio: 4.76). The <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">Relative Citation Ratio (RCR)</a> measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p>The gene <a href="https://www.proteinatlas.org/ENSG00000134883-ACBG2">ACBG2</a> functions as a blood group antigen and is an FDA-approved drug target involved in systemic lupus erythematosus. Evidence supports its expression at the protein level. The gene is detected in many tissues, with notable expression in the liver, where it is associated with metabolism (Cluster 83). In the brain, it is expressed in astrocytes with mixed functions (Cluster 39). Additionally, the gene is expressed in the DU4475 cell line and hepatocytes, where it is involved in metabolism (Cluster 62).</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD’s database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/3169">FOXA1</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/27161">AGO2</a>, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/23543">RBFOX2</a>, each shown to be regulating in one experiment.</p> <p>The analyzed protein sequence has a GRAVY value of -0.253 (63.52 percentile), indicating a hydrophilic nature. The charge at pH 7.0 is -2.654 (40.75 percentile), and the median structural flexibility is 1.0001 (42.03 percentile). The protein has a predicted secondary structure with 31.48% helix (45.55 percentile), 35.32% sheet (61.46 percentile), and 29.24% turn (57.97 percentile) affinities. The instability index is 45.99 (42.9 percentile), and the isoelectric point is 6.77 (47.51 percentile). The protein is 1744 amino acids long (96.48 percentile) with a molecular weight of 192766.16 Da (96.39 percentile). For more details on the sequence analysis, refer to the <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython documentation</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">yes</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="longest"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[C4B description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">C4BPB</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/C4BPB/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="C4BPB"/><published>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/C4BPB</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/C4BPB/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/725">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">725</td> <td style="text-align: left">C4BPB</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000123843</td> <td style="text-align: left">1q32.1</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene length is 1,104,578.0 base pairs (99.68% of all genes), the mature length is 2,432.0 base pairs, and the primary transcript length is 485,526.0 base pairs (99.19% of all genes).</p> <p>The gene C4BPB, with NCBI ID 725, has been the subject of <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22C4BPB%22">8 publications</a> (count from <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>, may differ from the hyperlink). The earliest year of publication is 1990, and the middle 50% of publications occurred between 1994 and 2011.</p> <p>The top 5 publications mentioning C4BPB, ranked by their relative citation ratio (RCR), which measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received and benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, are as follows:</p> <ol> <li><a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28278182">Serum amyloid A, protein Z, and C4b-binding protein β chain as new potential biomarkers for pulmonary tuberculosis.</a> (2017) (relative citation ratio: 1.41)</li> <li><a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20212171">C4BPB/C4BPA is a new susceptibility locus for venous thrombosis with unknown protein S-independent mechanism: results from genome-wide association and gene expression analyses followed by case-control studies.</a> (2010) (relative citation ratio: 1.24)</li> <li><a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7561114">Isoforms of human C4b-binding protein. II. Differential modulation of the C4BPA and C4BPB genes by acute phase cytokines.</a> (1995) (relative citation ratio: 0.59)</li> <li><a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25660618">An evaluation of association between common variants in C4BPB/C4BPA genes and schizophrenia.</a> (2015) (relative citation ratio: 0.43)</li> <li><a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2237642">Genes for C4b-binding protein alpha- and beta-chains (C4BPA and C4BPB) are located on chromosome 1, band 1q32, in humans and on chromosome 13 in rats.</a> (1990) (relative citation ratio: 0.41)</li> </ol> <p>The relative citation ratio (<a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">RCR</a>) values indicate the influence of these publications within their respective fields. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from GTRD’s database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/23476">BRD4</a> with 6 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/65980">BRD9</a> and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6599">SMARCC1</a> each with 4 experiments, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/4088">SMAD3</a> and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/54815">GATAD2A</a> each with 3 experiments.</p> <p>The genome-wide association study has identified a link between genetic variations and <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20212171">C4b binding protein levels</a>, with the closest MeSH match being <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D011506">Proteins</a>. This association was determined using the <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-019-0055-0">BioWordVec</a> method, which mapped the trait to its corresponding MeSH term through embedding match.</p> <p>The analyzed protein sequence has a GRAVY value of -0.276 (60.66th percentile), indicating a hydrophilic nature. At pH 7, the protein carries a charge of -11.1 (20.82nd percentile). The median structural flexibility is 1.002 (49.45th percentile), with a propensity for helix, sheet, and turn structures of 33.7% (65.65th percentile), 32.5% (42.65th percentile), and 28.2% (48.92nd percentile), respectively. The instability index is 34.9 (9.99th percentile), and the isoelectric point is 5.05 (8.69th percentile). The protein is 252 amino acids long (21.94th percentile) with a molecular weight of 28357.2 Da (22.36th percentile). For more details on sequence analysis, refer to <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython’s ProtParam documentation</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">yes</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="longest"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[C4BPB description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CCL11</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/CCL11/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CCL11"/><published>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-09T05:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/CCL11</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/CCL11/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6356">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">6356</td> <td style="text-align: left">CCL11</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000172156</td> <td style="text-align: left">17q12</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene length is 634,102.0 base pairs (98.97% of all genes), the mature length is 1,726.5 base pairs, and the primary transcript length is 574,227.5 base pairs (99.46% of all genes).</p> <p>The gene CCL11 has an NCBI Gene ID of 6356. It has been featured in <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22CCL11%22">406 publications</a> (note: count may differ as it is sourced from <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>). The earliest year of publication is 1994, and the middle 50% of publications occurred between 2000 and 2012.</p> <p>The top five publications mentioning CCL11, ranked by their scientific influence, include “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9302298">Selective expression of the eotaxin receptor CCR3 by human T helper 2 cells.</a>” (1997) (relative citation ratio: 17.87), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7509365">Eotaxin: a potent eosinophil chemoattractant cytokine detected in a guinea pig model of allergic airways inflammation.</a>” (1994) (relative citation ratio: 17.09), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8597956">Human eotaxin is a specific chemoattractant for eosinophil cells and provides a new mechanism to explain tissue eosinophilia.</a>” (1996) (relative citation ratio: 14.94), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8609214">Cloning of the human eosinophil chemoattractant, eotaxin. Expression, receptor binding, and functional properties suggest a mechanism for the selective recruitment of eosinophils.</a>” (1996) (relative citation ratio: 14.83), and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8676064">Molecular cloning and characterization of a human eotaxin receptor expressed selectively on eosinophils.</a>” (1996) (relative citation ratio: 11.86). The <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">Relative Citation Ratio (RCR)</a> measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p>The gene <a href="https://www.proteinatlas.org/[Ensembl]-[Gene]">Cytokine</a> is involved in cancer-related processes and has evidence at the protein level. It is detected in many tissues and is particularly expressed in the intestine, contributing to digestion. Additionally, it is found in connective tissue cells, playing a role in extracellular matrix organization. The gene is also involved in non-specific transcription processes.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2908">NR3C1</a> with 3 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6943">TCF21</a> with 1 experiment, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/55729">ATF7IP</a> with 1 experiment, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/5241">PGR</a> with 1 experiment, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/1387">CREBBP</a> with 1 experiment.</p> <p>The protein sequence analyzed has a GRAVY value of -0.172 (72nd percentile), indicating a hydrophilic nature. It exhibits a charge of 11.45 at pH 7.0 (84.19th percentile) and a median structural flexibility of 1.002 (52.15th percentile). The secondary structure affinities are notable, with 39.18% of residues tending to be in a helix (91.85th percentile), 32.99% in a sheet (45.43rd percentile), and 25.77% in a turn (27.3rd percentile). The instability index is 38.20 (17.36th percentile), and the isoelectric point is 9.98 (96.32nd percentile). The protein has a length of 97 amino acids (2.41st percentile) and a molecular weight of 10731.72 Da (2.32nd percentile). For more details on sequence analysis, refer to <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython’s ProtParam documentation</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">yes</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="longest"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[CCL11 description]]></summary></entry></feed>