<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-01-20T16:34:12+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A data-driven literature for understudied genes. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">AARS1</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/AARS1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AARS1"/><published>2025-01-17T22:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-17T22:55:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/AARS1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/AARS1/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/16">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">16</td> <td style="text-align: left">AARS1</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000090861</td> <td style="text-align: left">16q22.1</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene enables <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0000049">tRNA binding</a> and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0002161">aminoacyl-tRNA editing activity</a>, and is involved in <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0002196">Ser-tRNA(Ala) hydrolase activity</a> and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0004813">alanine-tRNA ligase activity</a>. It also enables <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005524">ATP binding</a> and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0008033">zinc ion binding</a>, and is active in <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0016597">amino acid binding</a>. The gene is located in the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005737">cytoplasm</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005739">mitochondrion</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005829">cytosol</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0016020">membrane</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0070062">extracellular exosome</a>. It is involved in various processes including <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0006400">tRNA modification</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0006418">tRNA aminoacylation for protein translation</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0006419">alanyl-tRNA aminoacylation</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0008033">tRNA processing</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0021680">cerebellar Purkinje cell layer development</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0043524">negative regulation of neuron apoptotic process</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0050885">neuromuscular process controlling balance</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0051402">neuron apoptotic process</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0106074">aminoacyl-tRNA metabolism involved in translational fidelity</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0140018">regulation of cytoplasmic translational fidelity</a>.</p> <p>The gene length is 174,633 base pairs (90.89% of all genes), the mature length is 5,578 base pairs (92.71% of all genes), and the primary transcript length is 140,143 base pairs (92.84% of all genes).</p> <p>The gene AARS1 (NCBI ID: 16) has been mentioned in <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22AARS1%22">45 publications</a> according to <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>, with the earliest publication in 1958 and the middle 50% of publications occurring between 2007 and 2019. Note that the publication count in the hyperlink may be different since the count is from Pubtator.</p> <p>The top 5 publications mentioning AARS1, ranked by their scientific influence, include “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3701255">Autoantibodies against alanyl-tRNA synthetase and tRNAAla coexist and are associated with myositis.</a>” (1986) (relative citation ratio: 5.14), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21549344">Exome sequencing identifies mitochondrial alanyl-tRNA synthetase mutations in infantile mitochondrial cardiomyopathy.</a>” (2011) (relative citation ratio: 4.56), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20045102">A major determinant for binding and aminoacylation of tRNA(Ala) in cytoplasmic Alanyl-tRNA synthetase is mutated in dominant axonal Charcot-Marie-Tooth disease.</a>” (2010) (relative citation ratio: 3.92), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23852030">Synthetic and editing mechanisms of aminoacyl-tRNA synthetases.</a>” (2014) (relative citation ratio: 3.26), and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2178410">Clinical manifestations in patients with antibody to PL-12 antigen (alanyl-tRNA synthetase).</a>” (1990) (relative citation ratio: 3.14). The <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">Relative Citation Ratio (RCR)</a> measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p><a href="https://www.proteinatlas.org/ENSG00000090861-AARS1">AARS1</a> is a gene with multiple molecular functions, including aminoacyl-tRNA synthetase, ligase, RNA-binding, and tRNA-binding. It is implicated in various diseases such as Charcot-Marie-Tooth disease, epilepsy, neurodegeneration, and neuropathy. Evidence for its function is available at the protein level. The gene is detected in all RNA tissue distributions and is primarily located in the cytosol. Its expression clusters include Cluster 33 for blood (non-specific - ATP binding), Cluster 32 for tissue (endocrine &amp; neural - unknown function), Cluster 45 for brain (non-specific - mixed function), Cluster 13 for cell line (non-specific - mixed function), and Cluster 61 for single cell (plasma cells - immunoglobulins &amp; histones).</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from GTRD’s database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/3169">FOXA1</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/10664">CTCF</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/3725">JUN</a>, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/5468">PPARG</a>, each with 4 experiments. Additionally, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2033">EP300</a> was found to be regulating in 3 experiments.</p> <p>The GWAS data indicates associations with various disease conditions, including cancer, diseases of cellular proliferation, metabolism, and nutrition. Specifically, the data highlights acquired metabolic diseases, overnutrition, and obesity. Additionally, there are associations with general diseases of anatomical entities, particularly kidney disease and urinary system diseases.</p> <p>The gene AARS1 has been associated with <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31669095">Body mass index</a>, which maps closely to the MeSH term <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D015992">Body Mass Index</a> using the method <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-019-0055-0">BioWordVec</a>.</p> <p>The gene is expressed in various tissues, including the thyroid and brain. Additionally, it is expressed in specific cell types associated with Lymphoma (Burkitt’s, Raji) and Leukemia (Chronic Myelogenous, K-562).</p> <p>The input data indicates involvement in several biological processes, including gene expression, cytosolic tRNA aminoacylation, and tRNA aminoacylation.</p> <p>The mouse ortholog gene 234734 and its human ortholog gene 16.0 are associated with the phenotype of preweaning lethality with complete penetrance, observed in both sexes.</p> <p>The protein sequence analyzed has a GRAVY value of -0.3042 (57.49th percentile), indicating a hydrophilic nature. At pH 7.0, the protein carries a charge of -23.97 (8.67th percentile). The median structural flexibility is 1.0040 (59.72nd percentile), with a predicted secondary structure composition of 34.71% helix (72.89th percentile), 34.30% sheet (54.02nd percentile), and 28.00% turn (47.23rd percentile). The instability index is 36.47 (13.0th percentile), and the isoelectric point is 5.34 (14.33rd percentile). The protein has a length of 968 amino acids (86.74th percentile) and a molecular weight of 106809.20 Da (86.46th percentile). For more details on the sequence analysis, refer to the <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython ProtParam documentation</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="unknown-mechanism"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[AARS1 description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ABCA8</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABCA8/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ABCA8"/><published>2025-01-17T22:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-17T22:55:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABCA8</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABCA8/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/10351">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">10351</td> <td style="text-align: left">ABCA8</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000141338</td> <td style="text-align: left">17q24.2</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene enables <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005319">lipid transporter activity</a> and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005524">ATP binding</a>, and is located in the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005783">endoplasmic reticulum</a> and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005886">plasma membrane</a>. It is involved in the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0006686">sphingomyelin biosynthetic process</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0006869">lipid transport</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0010874">regulation of cholesterol efflux</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0010875">positive regulation of cholesterol efflux</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0030301">cholesterol transport</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0033344">cholesterol efflux</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0042908">xenobiotic transport</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0055085">transmembrane transport</a>. Additionally, it enables <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0008559">ABC-type xenobiotic transporter activity</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0016887">ATP hydrolysis activity</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0042626">ATPase-coupled transmembrane transporter activity</a>. The gene is also active in the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0043231">intracellular membrane-bounded organelle</a> and is located in the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0016323">basolateral plasma membrane</a>.</p> <p>The gene length is 31,359.0 base pairs (53.9% of all genes), the mature length is 1,589.5 base pairs, and the primary transcript length is 29,931.5 base pairs.</p> <p>The gene ABCA8, with NCBI ID 10351, has been mentioned in <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22ABCA8%22">10 publications</a> (count may differ as it is from <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>). The earliest publication mentioning this gene was in 2002, and the middle 50% of publications occurred between 2013 and 2020.</p> <p>The top 5 publications mentioning ABCA8, ranked by their scientific influence, include “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12111378">Catalog of 605 single-nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) among 13 genes encoding human ATP-binding cassette transporters: ABCA4, ABCA7, ABCA8, ABCD1, ABCD3, ABCD4, ABCE1, ABCF1, ABCG1, ABCG2, ABCG4, ABCG5, and ABCG8.</a>” (2002) (relative citation ratio: 2.17), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28882873">ABCA8 Regulates Cholesterol Efflux and High-Density Lipoprotein Cholesterol Levels.</a>” (2017) (relative citation ratio: 1.82), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35191604">ABCA8 inhibits breast cancer cell proliferation by regulating the AMP activated protein kinase/mammalian target of rapamycin signaling pathway.</a>” (2022) (relative citation ratio: 1.8), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33431858">ABCA8-mediated efflux of taurocholic acid contributes to gemcitabine insensitivity in human pancreatic cancer via the S1PR2-ERK pathway.</a>” (2021) (relative citation ratio: 1.68), and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32430024">ABCA8 is regulated by miR-374b-5p and inhibits proliferation and metastasis of hepatocellular carcinoma through the ERK/ZEB1 pathway.</a>” (2020) (relative citation ratio: 1.31). The <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">Relative Citation Ratio (RCR)</a> measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p><a href="https://www.proteinatlas.org/ENSG00000141338-ABCA8">ABCA8</a> is a gene encoding a protein with translocase molecular function, supported by evidence at the protein level. The gene is detected in many tissues and is primarily localized in the nucleoplasm and cytosol. ABCA8 is notably expressed in smooth muscle tissue, where it is involved in extracellular matrix (ECM) organization, and in white matter, where it plays a role in signal transduction. Additionally, the gene is expressed in connective tissue cells and fibroblasts, contributing to ECM organization. While ABCA8 is not prognostic for several cancer types, it has been studied in various contexts, including breast invasive carcinoma, glioblastoma multiforme, and kidney renal clear cell carcinoma.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/10664">CTCF</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2099">ESR1</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2627">GATA6</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/3170">FOXA2</a>, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/7227">TRPS1</a>, each shown to be regulating in 3 experiments.</p> <p>The input data from GWAS indicates associations with a wide range of disease conditions, including various types of cancer such as breast cancer, thoracic cancer, male reproductive organ cancer, testicular cancer, head and neck cancer, colorectal cancer, intestinal cancer, large intestine cancer, gastrointestinal system cancer, myeloid leukemia, acute myeloid leukemia, colon cancer, and lung cancer. Additionally, the data highlights associations with infectious diseases like hand, foot and mouth disease, as well as metabolic disorders such as diabetes mellitus, type 2 diabetes mellitus, and cardiovascular conditions including coronary artery disease. Mental health conditions, including cognitive disorder, mood disorder, and mental depression, are also represented. Furthermore, the data includes associations with inherited metabolic disorders, lipid storage diseases, and lysosomal storage diseases.</p> <p>The gene ABCA8 has been associated with <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26830138">Alzheimer disease and age of onset</a> through genome-wide association studies.</p> <p>The gene is expressed in various neural tissues, including the nerve, trigeminal ganglion, atrioventricular node, ciliary ganglion, dorsal root ganglion, and olfactory bulb. Additionally, it is expressed in the ovary.</p> <p>The input data highlights two key pathways involving protein transport: ABC-family proteins mediated transport and transmembrane transport of small molecules.</p> <p>The protein sequence analyzed has a GRAVY value of 0.052 (86.18th percentile), indicating a slightly hydrophobic nature. At pH 7.0, the protein carries a charge of -0.795 (47.4th percentile). The median structural flexibility is 0.994 (17.82nd percentile), with a propensity for secondary structures as follows: 34.5% helix (71.47th percentile), 41.2% sheet (89.16th percentile), and 25.5% turn (25.04th percentile). The instability index is 36.65 (13.41st percentile), and the isoelectric point is 6.91 (49.4th percentile). The protein has a length of 1621 amino acids (95.83rd percentile) and a molecular weight of 183674.47 Da (96.03rd percentile). For more details on the sequence analysis, refer to the <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython documentation</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="unknown-mechanism"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ABCA8 description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ABCA9</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABCA9/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ABCA9"/><published>2025-01-17T22:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-17T22:55:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABCA9</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABCA9/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/10350">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">10350</td> <td style="text-align: left">ABCA9</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000154258</td> <td style="text-align: left">17q24.2</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene enables <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005319">lipid transporter activity</a> and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005524">ATP binding</a>, and is involved in <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0006869">lipid transport</a>. It is located in the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0016020">membrane</a> and is active in the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0043231">intracellular membrane-bounded organelle</a>. Additionally, it enables <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0016887">ATP hydrolysis activity</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0042626">ATPase-coupled transmembrane transporter activity</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0140359">ABC-type transporter activity</a>, and is involved in <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0055085">transmembrane transport</a>.</p> <p>The gene length is 248,863 base pairs (94.59% of all genes), the mature length is 2,382.5 base pairs, and the primary transcript length is 43,730.5 base pairs.</p> <p>The gene ABCA9, with NCBI ID 10350, has been mentioned in <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22ABCA9%22">1 publication</a> (count may differ as it is from <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>). The earliest year of publication is 2002, and the middle 50% of publications occurred between 2002 and 2002.</p> <p>The top publication mentioning ABCA9 is “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12150964">Molecular structure of a novel cholesterol-responsive A subclass ABC transporter, ABCA9.</a>” (2002) (relative citation ratio: 1.18). The <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">Relative Citation Ratio (RCR)</a> measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, and benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, the value of which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p><a href="https://www.proteinatlas.org/ENSG00000154258-ABCA9">ABCA9</a> is a translocase primarily located in the endoplasmic reticulum. Its RNA is detected in many tissues, with notable expression in smooth muscle tissue involved in ECM organization. In the brain, it shows non-specific expression with mixed functions. At the cellular level, ABCA9 is expressed in connective tissue cells and fibroblasts, both involved in ECM organization. Evidence for this gene is supported at the protein level.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2099">ESR1</a> with 4 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/23476">BRD4</a> with 3 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/3725">JUN</a> with 2 experiments, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6928">HNF1B</a> with 2 experiments.</p> <p>The GWAS data indicates associations with a range of disease conditions, including artery disease, vascular disease, cardiovascular system disease, kidney disease, urinary system disease, nervous system disease, central nervous system disease, neurodegenerative disease, amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, motor neuron disease, sensory system disease, and cerebrovascular disease.</p> <p>The gene is expressed in multiple tissue samples, including adipose tissue, breast, nerve, and ovary, as indicated by the BioGPS Human Cell Type and Tissue Gene Expression Profiles. Additionally, the GTEx Tissue Gene Expression Profiles show expression in the salivary gland and ovary.</p> <p>The input data highlights the involvement of ABC-family proteins in various transport processes. Specifically, these proteins mediate the transport of small molecules across membranes and play a crucial role in lipid homeostasis through ABCA transporters.</p> <p>The protein sequence analyzed has a GRAVY value of 0.087 (87.51% percentile), indicating a slightly hydrophobic nature. At pH 7.0, the protein carries a charge of -6.51 (29.58% percentile). The median structural flexibility is 0.992 (14.78% percentile), with a propensity for secondary structures as follows: 33.13% helix (60.35% percentile), 42.12% sheet (90.93% percentile), and 25.31% turn (23.74% percentile). The instability index is 36.35 (12.79% percentile), and the isoelectric point is 6.49 (42.4% percentile). The protein is 1624 amino acids long (95.85% percentile) with a molecular weight of 184359.36 Da (96.06% percentile). For more details on the sequence analysis, refer to the <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython documentation</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="unknown-mechanism"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ABCA9 description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ABCD3</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABCD3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ABCD3"/><published>2025-01-17T22:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-17T22:55:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABCD3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABCD3/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/5825">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">5825</td> <td style="text-align: left">ABCD3</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000117528</td> <td style="text-align: left">1p21.3</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene is involved in various metabolic processes, including <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0000038">very long-chain fatty acid metabolic process</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0006633">fatty acid biosynthetic process</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0006635">fatty acid beta-oxidation</a>. It enables several molecular functions such as <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005324">long-chain fatty acid transporter activity</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005515">protein binding</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005524">ATP binding</a>. The gene is located in multiple cellular components, including <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005739">mitochondrion</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005777">peroxisome</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005778">peroxisomal membrane</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005782">peroxisomal matrix</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005829">cytosol</a>. Additionally, it is involved in processes like <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0007031">peroxisome organization</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0009410">response to xenobiotic stimulus</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0015910">long-chain fatty acid import into peroxisome</a>. The gene also enables activities such as <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0016887">ATP hydrolysis activity</a> and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0042626">ATPase-coupled transmembrane transporter activity</a>.</p> <p>The gene length is 37,837 base pairs (58.91% of all genes), the mature length is 2,058 base pairs, and the primary transcript length is 37,697 base pairs.</p> <p>The gene ABCD3, with NCBI ID 5825, has been mentioned in <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22ABCD3%22">32 publications</a> according to <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>. The earliest year of publication is 1993, and the middle 50% of publications occurred between 2006 and 2018. Note that the publication count in the hyperlink may be different since the count is from Pubtator.</p> <p>The top five publications mentioning ABCD3, ranked by their scientific influence, include “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30540494">Peroxisomes can oxidize medium- and long-chain fatty acids through a pathway involving ABCD3 and HSD17B4.</a>” (2019) (relative citation ratio: 4.43), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25168382">A novel bile acid biosynthesis defect due to a deficiency of peroxisomal ABCD3.</a>” (2015) (relative citation ratio: 3.26), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24333844">A role for the human peroxisomal half-transporter ABCD3 in the oxidation of dicarboxylic acids.</a>” (2014) (relative citation ratio: 2.76), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12111378">Catalog of 605 single-nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) among 13 genes encoding human ATP-binding cassette transporters: ABCA4, ABCA7, ABCA8, ABCD1, ABCD3, ABCD4, ABCE1, ABCF1, ABCG1, ABCG2, ABCG4, ABCG5, and ABCG8.</a>” (2002) (relative citation ratio: 2.17), and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23532014">Validation of the ABCD3-I score to predict stroke risk after transient ischemic attack.</a>” (2013) (relative citation ratio: 1.39). The relative citation ratio (<a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">RCR</a>) measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p><a href="https://www.proteinatlas.org/ENSG00000117528-ABCD3">ABCD3</a> is a gene encoding a protein with hydrolase and translocase molecular functions, supported by evidence at the protein level. The gene is expressed in all tissues, with notable expression in the liver and intestine, where it is involved in lipid metabolism. Subcellularly, the protein is localized to peroxisomes. In the brain, ABCD3 is part of a non-specific transcription cluster, while in cell lines, it is associated with mRNA processing. Additionally, it is detected in basal prostatic cells, where it plays a role in lipid metabolism.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2033">EP300</a> with 6 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/3091">HIF1A</a> with 5 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/7003">TEAD1</a> with 5 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2624">GATA2</a> with 5 experiments, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/7528">YY1</a> with 5 experiments. These TFs have been shown to play significant roles in gene regulation, as evidenced by their frequent appearance in CHIP-seq data.</p> <p>The gene is expressed in multiple tissue samples, including liver, nerve, and colon, as indicated by the BioGPS Human Cell Type and Tissue Gene Expression Profiles. Additionally, the GTEx Tissue Gene Expression Profiles show expression in pineal gland (both day and night), amygdala, fetal brain, colon, small intestine, and fetal liver.</p> <p>The input data highlights the involvement of ABC-family proteins in various transport processes. Specifically, these proteins mediate the transport of small molecules across membranes and play a crucial role in lipid homeostasis through ABCA transporters.</p> <p>The mouse ortholog gene 19299 and its human ortholog 5825 are associated with several phenotypic abnormalities, including abnormal cholesterol homeostasis, decreased circulating triglyceride levels, impaired righting response, improved glucose tolerance, increased circulating alkaline phosphatase levels, increased circulating calcium levels, increased circulating total protein levels, increased lean body mass, and limb grasping. These phenotypes are observed in both sexes.</p> <p>The analyzed protein sequence has a GRAVY value of -0.130 (75.79th percentile), indicating a relatively hydrophilic nature. It exhibits a charge of 23.96 at pH 7.0 (95.4th percentile) and a median structural flexibility of 0.993 (16.23rd percentile). The protein’s secondary structure is predicted to be 32.63% helix (56.23rd percentile), 40.52% sheet (87.7th percentile), and 24.89% turn (20.82nd percentile). The instability index is 34.53 (9.25th percentile), with an isoelectric point of 9.41 (89.33rd percentile). The protein has a length of 659 amino acids (72.72nd percentile) and a molecular weight of 75475.03 Da (73.82nd percentile). For more details on the sequence analysis, refer to the <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython documentation</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="unknown-mechanism"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ABCD3 description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ABCE1</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABCE1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ABCE1"/><published>2025-01-17T22:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-17T22:55:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABCE1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABCE1/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6059">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">6059</td> <td style="text-align: left">ABCE1</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000164163</td> <td style="text-align: left">4q31.21</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene is involved in <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0000054">ribosomal subunit export from nucleus</a> and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0006413">translational initiation</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0006415">translational termination</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0006417">regulation of translation</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0032790">ribosome disassembly</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0072344">rescue of stalled ribosome</a>. It enables <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0003924">GTPase activity</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005506">iron ion binding</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005515">protein binding</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005524">ATP binding</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0016887">ATP hydrolysis activity</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0017111">ribonucleoside triphosphate phosphatase activity</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0043024">ribosomal small subunit binding</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0043273">CTPase activity</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0051539">4 iron, 4 sulfur cluster binding</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0060698">endoribonuclease inhibitor activity</a>. It is located in the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005737">cytoplasm</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005739">mitochondrion</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005759">mitochondrial matrix</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005829">cytosol</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0016020">membrane</a>, and is active in the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0022626">cytosolic ribosome</a>. Additionally, it is involved in the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0060702">negative regulation of endoribonuclease activity</a>.</p> <p>The gene length is 126,176 base pairs (86.09% of all genes), the mature length is 2,654 base pairs (66.88% of all genes), and the primary transcript length is 10,198 base pairs (33.8% of all genes).</p> <p>The gene ABCE1 (NCBI ID: 6059) has been mentioned in <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22ABCE1%22">70 publications</a> according to <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>, with the earliest publication in 1986 and the middle 50% of publications occurring between 2008 and 2018. Note that the publication count in the hyperlink may be different since the count is from Pubtator.</p> <p>The top five publications mentioning ABCE1, ranked by their scientific influence, include “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20122402">The role of ABCE1 in eukaryotic posttermination ribosomal recycling.</a>” (2010) with a relative citation ratio of 5.23, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21448132">Dissociation by Pelota, Hbs1 and ABCE1 of mammalian vacant 80S ribosomes and stalled elongation complexes.</a>” (2011) with a relative citation ratio of 4.48, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7539425">Cloning and characterization of a RNAse L inhibitor. A new component of the interferon-regulated 2-5A pathway.</a>” (1995) with a relative citation ratio of 3.98, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15660134">Biogenesis of cytosolic ribosomes requires the essential iron-sulphur protein Rli1p and mitochondria.</a>” (2005) with a relative citation ratio of 3.68, and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21292982">Ribosome recycling depends on a mechanistic link between the FeS cluster domain and a conformational switch of the twin-ATPase ABCE1.</a>” (2011) with a relative citation ratio of 2.74. The relative citation ratio (<a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">RCR</a>) measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p><a href="https://www.proteinatlas.org/ENSG00000164163-ABCE1">ABCE1</a> is a gene with molecular functions as a chaperone and hydrolase, supported by evidence at the protein level. Its RNA is detected in all tissues, and the protein is primarily located in the cytosol. ABCE1 is part of blood expression cluster 33, which is non-specific and involved in ATP binding, and tissue expression cluster 35, which is non-specific and related to mitochondria. In the brain, it is part of cluster 28, associated with oligodendrocytes and mixed functions. Additionally, ABCE1 is found in cell line expression cluster 22, which is non-specific and involved in mRNA splicing and the cell cycle, and single cell expression cluster 39, which is non-specific and related to basic cellular processes.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6774">STAT3</a> and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/3066">HDAC2</a>, each with 5 experiments. Additionally, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/8930">MBD4</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2078">ERG</a>, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/3169">FOXA1</a> were each found to be regulating in 4 experiments.</p> <p>The gene is expressed in various tissues and cell types, including skin, pineal gland (both day and night), B lymphoblasts (721), promyelocytic leukemia cells (HL-60), Burkitt’s lymphoma cells (Daudi), CD105+ endothelial cells, bronchial epithelial cells, and lymphoblastic leukemia cells (MOLT-4).</p> <p>The mouse ortholog gene 24015, which corresponds to the human ortholog gene 6059, is associated with several phenotypic abnormalities. These include abnormal seminal vesicle morphology, decreased prepulse inhibition, embryonic lethality prior to organogenesis, enlarged lymph nodes, and preweaning lethality with complete penetrance. Notably, decreased prepulse inhibition, enlarged lymph nodes, and preweaning lethality are observed in both sexes, while abnormal seminal vesicle morphology and embryonic lethality prior to organogenesis are not.</p> <p>The analyzed protein sequence has a GRAVY value of -0.191 (70.11th percentile), indicating a relatively hydrophilic nature. The charge at pH 7.0 is 9.191 (79.91st percentile), and the median structural flexibility is 1.0002 (42.54th percentile). The protein has a predicted affinity for helix, sheet, and turn structures of 33.22% (61.26th percentile), 37.06% (73.48th percentile), and 26.04% (29.59th percentile), respectively. The instability index is 33.99 (8.53rd percentile), and the isoelectric point is 8.63 (69.41st percentile). The protein is 599 amino acids long (68.51st percentile) with a molecular weight of 67313.58 Da (68.75th percentile). For more details on the sequence analysis, refer to the <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython documentation</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="unknown-mechanism"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ABCE1 description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ABCG1</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABCG1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ABCG1"/><published>2025-01-17T22:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-17T22:55:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABCG1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABCG1/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/9619">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">9619</td> <td style="text-align: left">ABCG1</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000160179</td> <td style="text-align: left">21q22.3</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene is located in the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0000139">Golgi membrane</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005739">mitochondrion</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005768">endosome</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005789">endoplasmic reticulum membrane</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005794">Golgi apparatus</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005886">plasma membrane</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0009897">external side of plasma membrane</a>. It enables <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005515">protein binding</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005524">ATP binding</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005543">phospholipid binding</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0015485">cholesterol binding</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0016887">ATP hydrolysis activity</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0019534">toxin transmembrane transporter activity</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0034041">ABC-type sterol transporter activity</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0042803">protein homodimerization activity</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0046982">protein heterodimerization activity</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0043531">ADP binding</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0090554">phosphatidylcholine floppase activity</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0120020">cholesterol transfer activity</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0140328">floppase activity</a>. The gene is involved in various processes including <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0008203">cholesterol metabolic process</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0010033">response to organic substance</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0010745">negative regulation of macrophage derived foam cell differentiation</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0010875">positive regulation of cholesterol efflux</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0010887">negative regulation of cholesterol storage</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0032367">intracellular cholesterol transport</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0033344">cholesterol efflux</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0033700">phospholipid efflux</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0033993">response to lipid</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0034204">lipid translocation</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0034374">low-density lipoprotein particle remodeling</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0034375">high-density lipoprotein particle remodeling</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0034436">glycoprotein transport</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0042632">cholesterol homeostasis</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0042987">amyloid precursor protein catabolic process</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0043691">reverse cholesterol transport</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0045542">positive regulation of cholesterol biosynthetic process</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0050714">positive regulation of protein secretion</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0055085">transmembrane transport</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0055091">phospholipid homeostasis</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0071403">cellular response to high density lipoprotein particle stimulus</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0090181">regulation of cholesterol metabolic process</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0120009">intermembrane lipid transfer</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:1901998">toxin transport</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:1902004">positive regulation of amyloid-beta formation</a>.</p> <p>The gene length is 79,916 base pairs (77.36% of all genes), the mature length is 1,254 base pairs (30.67% of all genes), and the primary transcript length is 62,975 base pairs (80.31% of all genes).</p> <p>The gene ABCG1 (NCBI ID: 9619) has been mentioned in <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22ABCG1%22">185 publications</a> (count from <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>, may differ from the hyperlink count). The earliest year of publication mentioning this gene is 1981, and the middle 50% of publications occurred between 2009 and 2018.</p> <p>The top five publications mentioning ABCG1, ranked by their scientific influence, include “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16054053">ABCG1 has a critical role in mediating cholesterol efflux to HDL and preventing cellular lipid accumulation.</a>” (2005) (relative citation ratio: 13.59), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35063134">ABCA1 and ABCG1 as potential therapeutic targets for the prevention of atherosclerosis.</a>” (2022) (relative citation ratio: 13.05), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19797709">Role of HDL, ABCA1, and ABCG1 transporters in cholesterol efflux and immune responses.</a>” (2010) (relative citation ratio: 12.72), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16357317">ABCA1 and ABCG1 synergize to mediate cholesterol export to apoA-I.</a>” (2006) (relative citation ratio: 7.27), and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23572498">Deficiency of ATP-binding cassette transporters A1 and G1 in macrophages increases inflammation and accelerates atherosclerosis in mice.</a>” (2013) (relative citation ratio: 6.47). The <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">Relative Citation Ratio (RCR)</a> measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p><a href="https://www.proteinatlas.org/ENSG00000160179-ABCG1">ABCG1</a> is a translocase with evidence at the protein level. It is detected in all tissues and is primarily localized in the Golgi apparatus and vesicles. ABCG1 is expressed in neutrophils with unknown function, the parathyroid gland involved in vesicular transport, oligodendrocytes with mixed function, leukemia T-cell receptor, and macrophages involved in innate immune response.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD database, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2146">EZH2</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6667">SP1</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/367">AR</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/4297">KMT2A</a>, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2099">ESR1</a>, each shown to be regulating in 4 experiments.</p> <p>The input data highlights a wide range of disease conditions associated with various biological systems. These include several types of cancer, such as lung cancer, respiratory system cancer, and organ system cancer. Additionally, the data encompasses hematopoietic and immune system diseases, including leukocyte disease, leukopenia, and immune system disease. Metabolic disorders are also prominent, with conditions like diabetes mellitus, type 2 diabetes mellitus, and obesity being noted. Cardiovascular diseases, such as coronary artery disease and heart disease, are also included. Furthermore, the data covers nervous system diseases, including neurodegenerative diseases like Parkinson’s disease, as well as cognitive disorders and diseases of mental health. Substance-related disorders, specifically alcohol dependence, are also mentioned. The data also includes primary immunodeficiency diseases, such as agammaglobulinemia and common variable immunodeficiency, as well as specific lung carcinomas like non-small cell lung carcinoma.</p> <p>The gene is expressed in multiple tissue samples, including the adrenal gland, lung, and spleen, as indicated by the BioGPS Human Cell Type and Tissue Gene Expression Profiles. Additionally, the GTEx Tissue Gene Expression Profiles show expression in the retina, lung, placenta, pancreatic islet, adrenal gland, thymus, and leukemia lymphoblastic (MOLT-4).</p> <p>The proteins are involved in various pathways related to lipid metabolism and transport, including ABC-family proteins mediated transport, ABCA transporters in lipid homeostasis, lipid digestion, mobilization, and transport, lipoprotein metabolism, and HDL-mediated lipid transport. Additionally, they participate in broader metabolic processes and the transmembrane transport of small molecules.</p> <p>The protein sequence analyzed has a GRAVY value of 0.163 (89.62 percentile), indicating a relatively hydrophobic nature. At pH 7.0, the protein carries a charge of 3.54 (62.91 percentile). The median structural flexibility is 0.992 (13.61 percentile), with a propensity for helix, sheet, and turn structures of 33.5% (63.56 percentile), 39.7% (85.25 percentile), and 26.8% (36.6 percentile), respectively. The instability index is 37.43 (15.16 percentile), and the isoelectric point is 8.02 (59.07 percentile). The protein has a length of 678 amino acids (74.01 percentile) and a molecular weight of 75591.23 Da (73.89 percentile). For more details on the sequence analysis, refer to the <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython documentation</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">yes</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="unknown-mechanism"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ABCG1 description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ABCG2</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABCG2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ABCG2"/><published>2025-01-17T22:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-17T22:55:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABCG2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABCG2/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/9429">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">9429</td> <td style="text-align: left">ABCG2</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000118777</td> <td style="text-align: left">4q22.1</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene enables <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005515">protein binding</a> and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005524">ATP binding</a>, and is located in the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005654">nucleoplasm</a> and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005886">plasma membrane</a>. It is involved in <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0006869">lipid transport</a> and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0015711">organic anion transport</a>, and enables various transporter activities, including <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0008514">organic anion transmembrane transporter activity</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0008559">ABC-type xenobiotic transporter activity</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0015143">urate transmembrane transporter activity</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0015225">biotin transmembrane transporter activity</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0015562">efflux transmembrane transporter activity</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0032217">riboflavin transmembrane transporter activity</a>. Additionally, it is involved in processes such as <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0015747">urate transport</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0015878">biotin transport</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0032218">riboflavin transport</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0055085">transmembrane transport</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0070633">transepithelial transport</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0097744">renal urate salt excretion</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0140115">export across plasma membrane</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0150104">transport across blood-brain barrier</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:1990748">cellular detoxification</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:1990962">xenobiotic transport across blood-brain barrier</a>. The gene is also located in the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0016324">apical plasma membrane</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0031526">brush border membrane</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0031966">mitochondrial membrane</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0045121">membrane raft</a>, and the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0098591">external side of apical plasma membrane</a>. Furthermore, it enables <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0016887">ATP hydrolysis activity</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0042626">ATPase-coupled transmembrane transporter activity</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0042802">identical protein binding</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0042803">protein homodimerization activity</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0042910">xenobiotic transmembrane transporter activity</a>.</p> <p>The gene length is 31,350 base pairs (53.89% of all genes), the mature length is 3,215 base pairs, and the primary transcript length is 31,299 base pairs.</p> <p>The gene ABCG2, with NCBI ID 9429, has been mentioned in <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22ABCG2%22">1,500 publications</a> (note: count may differ as it is sourced from <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>). The earliest year of publication mentioning this gene is 1976, and the middle 50% of publications occurred between 2009 and 2018.</p> <p>The top 5 publications mentioning ABCG2, ranked by their scientific influence, include “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35152405">The Clinical Pharmacogenetics Implementation Consortium Guideline for SLCO1B1, ABCG2, and CYP2C9 genotypes and Statin-Associated Musculoskeletal Symptoms.</a>” (2022) (relative citation ratio: 25.71), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11309308">Subcellular localization and distribution of the breast cancer resistance protein transporter in normal human tissues.</a>” (2001) (relative citation ratio: 21.83), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9806540">A gene encoding a liver-specific ABC transporter is mutated in progressive familial intrahepatic cholestasis.</a>” (1998) (relative citation ratio: 17.2), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9850061">A human placenta-specific ATP-binding cassette gene (ABCP) on chromosome 4q22 that is involved in multidrug resistance.</a>” (1998) (relative citation ratio: 16.03), and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19265662">PTEN/PI3K/Akt pathway regulates the side population phenotype and ABCG2 activity in glioma tumor stem-like cells.</a>” (2009) (relative citation ratio: 14.34). The <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">Relative Citation Ratio (RCR)</a> measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p><a href="https://www.proteinatlas.org/ENSG00000118777-ABCG2">ABCG2</a> is a translocase involved in cancer-related genes, with evidence at the protein level. It is detected in many tissues and is localized in the nucleoplasm and plasma membrane. ABCG2 is expressed in NK-cells of unknown function, small intestine absorption cells, endothelial cells of the vasculature, squamous epithelial cells involved in keratinization, and basal prostatic cells involved in lipid metabolism.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2313">FLI1</a> with 6 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6597">SMARCA4</a> with 5 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/23476">BRD4</a> with 5 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2146">EZH2</a> with 5 experiments, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/4613">MYCN</a> with 5 experiments. These TFs have been shown to play significant roles in gene regulation, as evidenced by their frequent appearance in CHIP-seq data.</p> <p>The GWAS data indicates associations with a wide range of disease conditions, including infectious diseases such as viral infectious disease and human immunodeficiency virus infectious disease. Additionally, the data highlights associations with hematopoietic system disease, immune system disease, and various cardiovascular conditions such as coronary artery disease, artery disease, vascular disease, and cardiovascular system disease. Furthermore, the data includes associations with kidney disease, urinary system disease, arteriosclerosis, atherosclerosis, and several musculoskeletal conditions such as bone inflammation disease, arthritis, bone disease, connective tissue disease, and gout. The data also points to associations with gastrointestinal system disease, myocardial infarction, and dental conditions including dental caries, teeth hard tissue disease, mouth disease, and tooth disease.</p> <p>ABCG2 has been associated with various traits and diseases through genome-wide association studies. Notably, it has been linked to <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/36635386">3-bromo-5-chloro-2,6-dihydroxybenzoic acid levels</a>, which maps to the MeSH term <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D000143">Acids</a> using the BioWordVec method. Additionally, ABCG2 is associated with <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/36357675">4-hydroxychlorothalonil levels</a>, mapped to the MeSH term <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D008731">Methoxychlor</a>, and <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33287642">Caffeine consumption from coffee or tea</a>, mapped to the MeSH term <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D003069">Coffee</a>. A significant association is also seen with <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21983786">Gout</a>, directly mapped to the MeSH term <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D006073">Gout</a>. Other associations include <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33832965">Gout vs asymptomatic hyperuricemia</a>, mapped to <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D033461">Hyperuricemia</a>, and <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29124443">Hyperuricemia</a>, directly mapped to the MeSH term <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D033461">Hyperuricemia</a>. Furthermore, ABCG2 is linked to <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/37277652">Plasma sulfate of piperine metabolite C18H21NO3 (1)* levels in chronic kidney disease</a>, mapped to the MeSH term <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D010949">Plasma</a>, and <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30181573">Serum urate levels in chronic kidney disease</a>, mapped to the MeSH term <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D007668">Kidney</a>. These associations highlight the diverse roles of ABCG2 in various biological processes and diseases.</p> <p>The gene is expressed in various tissues, including the prefrontal cortex, CD71+ early erythroid cells, hypothalamus, occipital lobe, placenta, small intestine, and uterus.</p> <p>The input data highlights several key biological processes, including metabolism, iron uptake and transport, abacavir transmembrane transport, abacavir transport and metabolism, and the transmembrane transport of small molecules. These pathways are integral to cellular function and homeostasis, encompassing both general metabolic activities and specialized transport mechanisms.</p> <p>The mouse ortholog gene 26357 and its human ortholog gene 9429 are associated with the phenotypes of ‘fused cornea and lens’ and ‘increased circulating HDL cholesterol level’, both of which are observed in both sexes.</p> <p>The protein sequence analyzed has a GRAVY value of 0.195 (90.38th percentile), indicating a relatively hydrophobic nature. It exhibits a charge of 11.3 at pH 7.0 (83.97th percentile) and a median structural flexibility of 0.992 (14.27th percentile). The protein’s secondary structure is predicted to be 32.5% helix (55.24th percentile), 41.5% sheet (89.81st percentile), and 27.9% turn (46.67th percentile). The instability index is 29.3 (3.44th percentile), suggesting a stable protein. The isoelectric point is 8.91 (76.73rd percentile), with a length of 655 amino acids (72.48th percentile) and a molecular weight of 72313.3 Da (72.03rd percentile). For more details on the sequence analysis, refer to the <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython documentation</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">yes</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="unknown-mechanism"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ABCG2 description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ABI2</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABI2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ABI2"/><published>2025-01-17T22:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-17T22:55:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABI2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABI2/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/10152">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">10152</td> <td style="text-align: left">ABI2</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000138443</td> <td style="text-align: left">2q33.2</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene is involved in various biological processes, including <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0001764">neuron migration</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0007010">cytoskeleton organization</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0007399">nervous system development</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0008154">actin polymerization or depolymerization</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0010592">positive regulation of lamellipodium assembly</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0016477">cell migration</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0016601">Rac protein signal transduction</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0061001">regulation of dendritic spine morphogenesis</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0070309">lens fiber cell morphogenesis</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:2000601">positive regulation of Arp2/3 complex-mediated actin nucleation</a>. It enables functions such as <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005515">protein binding</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0008093">cytoskeletal anchor activity</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0017124">SH3 domain binding</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0019900">kinase binding</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0031625">ubiquitin protein ligase binding</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0035591">signaling adaptor activity</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0042802">identical protein binding</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0070064">proline-rich region binding</a>. The gene is located in the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005634">nucleus</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005737">cytoplasm</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005829">cytosol</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005856">cytoskeleton</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005912">adherens junction</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0030027">lamellipodium</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0032433">filopodium tip</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0043197">dendritic spine</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0098858">actin-based cell projection</a>. Additionally, it is part of the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0031209">SCAR complex</a> and acts upstream of or within <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0018108">peptidyl-tyrosine phosphorylation</a>.</p> <p>The gene length is 33,294 base pairs (55.5% of all genes), the mature length is 585 base pairs, and the primary transcript length is 21,345 base pairs.</p> <p>The gene ABI2 (NCBI ID: 10152) has been mentioned in <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22ABI2%22">15 publications</a> according to <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>, with the earliest publication in 1995 and the middle 50% of publications occurring between 2003 and 2017. Note that the publication count in the hyperlink may be different since the count is from Pubtator.</p> <p>The top 5 publications mentioning ABI2, ranked by their scientific influence, include studies that explore the gene’s role in various biological processes. The Relative Citation Ratio (<a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">RCR</a>) measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Notable publications include “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9090884">Differential abscisic acid regulation of guard cell slow anion channels in Arabidopsis wild-type and abi1 and abi2 mutants.</a>” (1997) (relative citation ratio: 6.95), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29275167">Abscisic Acid Signaling Inhibits Brassinosteroid Signaling through Dampening the Dephosphorylation of BIN2 by ABI1 and ABI2.</a>” (2018) (relative citation ratio: 5.2), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10488243">Arabidopsis abi1-1 and abi2-1 phosphatase mutations reduce abscisic acid-induced cytoplasmic calcium rises in guard cells.</a>” (1999) (relative citation ratio: 4.13), “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7590236">Abi-2, a novel SH3-containing protein interacts with the c-Abl tyrosine kinase and modulates c-Abl transforming activity.</a>” (1995) (relative citation ratio: 4.11), and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28631860">ABi<sub>2</sub> (IO<sub>3</sub> )<sub>2</sub> F<sub>5</sub> (A=K, Rb, and Cs): A Combination of Halide and Oxide Anionic Units To Create a Large Second-Harmonic Generation Response with a Wide Bandgap.</a>” (2017) (relative citation ratio: 3.29). The citation count is sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p><a href="https://www.proteinatlas.org/ENSG00000138443-ABI2">ABI2</a> is a gene with evidence at the protein level, implicated in intellectual disability. It is detected in all tissues and is primarily localized in the nucleoplasm, vesicles, and cytosol. ABI2 is expressed in various clusters, including Cluster 8 in plasmacytoid DCs with unknown function, Cluster 64 in neuronal tissues related to transcription, Cluster 33 in brain neurons with mixed function, Cluster 26 in non-specific cell lines associated with mitochondria and RNA binding, and Cluster 9 in endometrial stromal cells related to transcription.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from GTRD’s database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/79733">E2F8</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6872">TAF1</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/3170">FOXA2</a>, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/10320">IKZF1</a>, each with 5 experiments. Additionally, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/9126">SMC3</a> was found to be regulating in 4 experiments.</p> <p>The GWAS data indicates associations with various disease conditions, including diseases of metabolism, acquired metabolic diseases, carbohydrate metabolism diseases, glucose metabolism diseases, diabetes mellitus, and specifically type 2 diabetes mellitus. Additionally, the data highlights nutrition diseases, overnutrition, obesity, artery diseases, vascular diseases, and cardiovascular system diseases. Other notable associations include arteriosclerosis, arteriosclerotic cardiovascular disease, and atherosclerosis.</p> <p>The gene is expressed in various neural tissues, including the brain and pituitary, as indicated by the BioGPS Human Cell Type and Tissue Gene Expression Profiles. Additionally, the GTEx Tissue Gene Expression Profiles show expression in the Superior Cervical Ganglion, Trigeminal Ganglion, and multiple regions of the testis, including the interstitial tissue, Leydig cells, seminiferous tubules, and germ cells.</p> <p>The input data highlights several key pathways involved in the immune system, including the innate immune system, signaling by VEGF, and the VEGFA-VEGFR2 pathway. Additionally, it covers Fcgamma receptor (FCGR) dependent phagocytosis, regulation of actin dynamics for phagocytic cup formation, and signal transduction.</p> <p>The mouse ortholog gene 329165, which corresponds to the human ortholog gene 10152, is associated with several phenotypic abnormalities. These include abnormal cornea morphology and abnormal iris morphology, both observed in both sexes. Additionally, the gene is linked to abnormal iris pigmentation, abnormal seminal vesicle morphology, absent urinary bladder, and small testis, although these phenotypes are not observed in both sexes.</p> <p>The analyzed protein sequence has a GRAVY value of -0.612 (24.21% percentile), indicating a hydrophilic nature. The charge at pH 7.0 is -6.65 (29.32% percentile), and the median structural flexibility is 1.011 (84.89% percentile). The protein has a propensity for helix, sheet, and turn structures of 24.56% (4.3% percentile), 30.41% (30.47% percentile), and 39.38% (96.91% percentile), respectively. The instability index is 74.19 (96.61% percentile), suggesting high instability. The isoelectric point is 5.82 (25.74% percentile), with a molecular weight of 55662.56 Da (58.06% percentile). The sequence length is 513 amino acids (59.84% percentile). For more details on sequence analysis, refer to <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython’s ProtParam documentation</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">yes</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="unknown-mechanism"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ABI2 description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ABLIM1</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABLIM1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ABLIM1"/><published>2025-01-17T22:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-17T22:55:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABLIM1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABLIM1/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/3983">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">3983</td> <td style="text-align: left">ABLIM1</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000099204</td> <td style="text-align: left">10q25.3</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene is located in the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005737">cytoplasm</a> and is active in the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0001725">stress fiber</a> and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0015629">actin cytoskeleton</a>. It enables <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0003779">actin binding</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005515">protein binding</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0051015">actin filament binding</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0046872">metal ion binding</a>. The gene is involved in various processes including <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0007010">cytoskeleton organization</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0007601">visual perception</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0009887">animal organ morphogenesis</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0030032">lamellipodium assembly</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0060271">cilium assembly</a>. Additionally, it is located in the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0030027">lamellipodium</a> and acts upstream of or within <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0030032">lamellipodium assembly</a> and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0060271">cilium assembly</a>.</p> <p>The gene has a length of 27,864 base pairs (50.64% of all genes), a mature length of 489 base pairs, and a primary transcript length of 23,633 base pairs.</p> <p>The gene ABLIM1 (NCBI ID: 3983) has been mentioned in <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22ABLIM1%22">11 publications</a> (count from <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>, may differ from the hyperlink). The earliest publication mentioning this gene was in 1997, and the middle 50% of publications occurred between 2006 and 2018.</p> <p>The top 5 publications mentioning ABLIM1, ranked by their scientific influence, include studies that explore the gene’s role in various biological processes. The Relative Citation Ratio (<a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">RCR</a>) measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. The most influential publication is “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12526772">The netrin receptor UNC-40/DCC stimulates axon attraction and outgrowth through enabled and, in parallel, Rac and UNC-115/AbLIM.</a>” (2003) (relative citation ratio: 2.74). Another notable study is “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9245787">Molecular characterization of abLIM, a novel actin-binding and double zinc finger protein.</a>” (1997) (relative citation ratio: 1.87). Additionally, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32606725">LncRNA <i>ZNF667-AS1</i> Promotes <i>ABLIM1</i> Expression by Adsorbing <i>micro</i> <i>RNA-1290</i> to Suppress Nasopharyngeal Carcinoma Cell Progression.</a>” (2020) (relative citation ratio: 1.13) and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19799769">The Arp2/3 complex, UNC-115/abLIM, and UNC-34/Enabled regulate axon guidance and growth cone filopodia formation in Caenorhabditis elegans.</a>” (2009) (relative citation ratio: 0.94) are also significant. Lastly, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25403273">ABLIM1 splicing is abnormal in skeletal muscle of patients with DM1 and regulated by MBNL, CELF and PTBP1.</a>” (2015) (relative citation ratio: 0.56) contributes to the understanding of ABLIM1. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p><a href="https://www.proteinatlas.org/ENSG00000099204-ABLIM1">ABLIM1</a> is an actin-binding protein with evidence at the protein level. It is detected in all tissues and is primarily localized in the cytosol, connecting piece, and mid piece. The gene is expressed in various clusters, including Cluster 43 for non-specific transcription and translation in blood, Cluster 12 for heart muscle and cardiac muscle contraction in tissues, Cluster 35 for non-specific DNA binding in the brain, Cluster 15 for kidney cancer membrane components in cell lines, and Cluster 47 for astrocytes with unknown function in single cells.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/3172">HNF4A</a> with 6 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6597">SMARCA4</a> with 5 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/367">AR</a> with 5 experiments, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6599">SMARCC1</a> with 5 experiments, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/6595">SMARCA2</a> with 4 experiments. These TFs have been shown to play significant roles in gene regulation, as evidenced by their frequent appearance in CHIP-seq data.</p> <p>The input data from GWAS indicates associations with a wide range of disease conditions, including various types of cancer such as male reproductive organ cancer, prostate cancer, lung cancer, and urinary system cancer. Additionally, respiratory system diseases like asthma, bronchial disease, and obstructive lung disease are noted. Metabolic and cardiovascular conditions, including obesity, coronary artery disease, and heart disease, are also represented. Neurodegenerative diseases such as Alzheimer’s disease, tauopathy, and dementia, along with mental health disorders like bipolar disorder, major depressive disorder, and mood disorder, are included. Furthermore, gastrointestinal system diseases like intestinal disease and colonic disease, as well as urinary system diseases like kidney disease and bladder carcinoma, are part of the dataset.</p> <p>The gene is expressed in various tissues, including the heart and ovary, as indicated by the BioGPS Human Cell Type and Tissue Gene Expression Profiles. Additionally, the GTEx Tissue Gene Expression Profiles show expression in pineal gland (night), CD4+ T cells, CD8+ T cells, CD19+ B cells (negatively selected), cerebellum, cerebellum peduncles, colorectal adenocarcinoma, and tongue.</p> <p>The proteins are involved in several pathways, including axon guidance, developmental biology, DCC-mediated attractive signaling, and netrin-1 signaling.</p> <p>The mouse ortholog gene 226251 and its human ortholog gene 3983 are associated with a decreased thermal nociceptive threshold. This phenotype was observed in a sex-specific manner.</p> <p>The analyzed protein sequence has a GRAVY value of -0.716 (16.67th percentile), indicating a hydrophilic nature. It exhibits a charge of 23.8 at pH 7.0 (95.33rd percentile) and a median structural flexibility of 1.004 (61.53rd percentile). The protein’s secondary structure is predicted to be 26.99% helix (11.69th percentile), 28.53% sheet (20.82nd percentile), and 31.88% turn (76.04th percentile). Additionally, the protein has an instability index of 58.81 (80.78th percentile), an isoelectric point of 8.91 (76.78th percentile), a length of 778 amino acids (79.62nd percentile), and a molecular weight of 87686.63 Da (79.92nd percentile). These calculations were performed using BioPython’s sequence analysis tools, which can be explored further <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">here</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="unknown-mechanism"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ABLIM1 description]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ABO</title><link href="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABO/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ABO"/><published>2025-01-17T22:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-17T22:55:00+00:00</updated><id>https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABO</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://spencer-hong.github.io/read-about-genes/genes/ABO/"><![CDATA[<table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/28">NCBI ID</a></th> <th style="text-align: left">NCBI symbol</th> <th style="text-align: left">ENSEMBL ID</th> <th style="text-align: left">Chromosome location</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">28</td> <td style="text-align: left">ABO</td> <td style="text-align: left">ENSG00000175164</td> <td style="text-align: left">9q34.2</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The gene is located in the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0000139">Golgi membrane</a> and the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005576">extracellular region</a>, specifically within the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0032580">Golgi cisterna membrane</a>. It is active in the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005794">Golgi apparatus</a> and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0031982">vesicle</a>. The gene enables <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0000166">nucleotide binding</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0003823">antigen binding</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0004380">glycoprotein-fucosylgalactoside alpha-N-acetylgalactosaminyltransferase activity</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0004381">fucosylgalactoside 3-alpha-galactosyltransferase activity</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0030145">manganese ion binding</a>. Additionally, it is involved in the <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0005975">carbohydrate metabolic process</a>, <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0006486">protein glycosylation</a>, and <a href="https://amigo.geneontology.org/amigo/term/GO:0030259">lipid glycosylation</a>.</p> <p>The gene has a length of 8,142 base pairs (21.64% of all genes), a mature length of 907.5 base pairs, and a primary transcript length of 2,099 base pairs.</p> <p>The ABO gene (NCBI ID: 28) has been mentioned in <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=%22ABO%22">5,271 publications</a> (count from <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/47/W1/W587/5494727">Pubtator</a>, may differ from the hyperlink count). The earliest year of publication is 1947, and the middle 50% of publications range from 1976 to 2014.</p> <p>The top five publications mentioning the ABO gene, ranked by their scientific influence, include “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32750119">Relationship Between the ABO Blood Group and the Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Susceptibility.</a>” (2021) with a <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002541">Relative Citation Ratio (RCR)</a> of 41.21, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2333095">Molecular genetic basis of the histo-blood group ABO system.</a>” (1990) with an RCR of 21.29, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3495304">The effect of ABO blood group on the diagnosis of von Willebrand disease.</a>” (1987) with an RCR of 20.86, “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32379894">Association between ABO blood groups and risk of SARS-CoV-2 pneumonia.</a>” (2020) with an RCR of 16.05, and “<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2433836">Genetics of ABO, H, Lewis, X and related antigens.</a>” (1986) with an RCR of 11.58. The Relative Citation Ratio (RCR) measures the scientific influence of each paper by field- and time-adjusting the citations it has received, benchmarking to the median for NIH publications, which is set at 1.0. Citation counts are sourced from <a href="https://icite.od.nih.gov">iCite</a>.</p> <p>The <a href="https://www.proteinatlas.org/ENSG00000175164-ABO">ABO</a> gene, with evidence at the transcript level, is detected in many tissues. It is associated with Cluster 20 in blood expression, which is non-specific for DNA binding, and Cluster 45 in tissue expression, which is specific to the intestine and digestion. In brain expression, it falls under Cluster 31, which is non-specific for transcription. Additionally, the gene is linked to Cluster 53 in cell line expression, specific to squamous epithelial cells and keratinization, and Cluster 22 in single cell expression, specific to proximal enterocytes and digestion.</p> <p>The top transcription factors (TFs) identified from the GTRD database of TF binding sites, based on the number of CHIP-seq experiments, include <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/23512">SUZ12</a> and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/4609">MYC</a>, each with 5 experiments. Additionally, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/861">RUNX1</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/23476">BRD4</a>, and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/2146">EZH2</a> were each found to be regulating in 4 experiments.</p> <p>The input data from GWAS indicates associations with a wide range of disease conditions, including various types of cancer such as gastrointestinal system cancer, leukemia, lymphoma, and hematologic cancer. Infectious diseases, particularly those caused by viral agents like human immunodeficiency virus, are also represented. Metabolic disorders, including diabetes mellitus, specifically type 2 diabetes mellitus, and obesity, are notable. Cardiovascular diseases, such as coronary artery disease and myocardial infarction, are included, along with kidney disease and urinary system disease. Additionally, the data encompasses liver diseases, including hepatocellular carcinoma and fatty liver disease, as well as endocrine system diseases like Graves’ disease and hyperthyroidism. Infectious diseases caused by parasitic protozoa, such as malaria, are also mentioned. The data further includes conditions like sarcoidosis, cerebrovascular disease, and various types of cancer affecting different organ systems, including pancreatic cancer and esophageal cancer.</p> <p>Genome-wide association studies have identified several traits and diseases associated with the ABO blood group system. Notably, <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33462484">Alanine aminotransferase levels</a> were mapped to <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D000637">Transaminases</a> using BioWordVec. Additionally, <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33067605">Angiopoietin-1 receptor levels</a> and <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34814699">Angiopoietin-1 receptor, soluble levels</a> were both mapped to <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D042683">Angiopoietin-1</a>. <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34648354">Angiotensin-converting enzyme levels</a> were associated with <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D004798">Enzymes</a>, and <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33462484">Apolipoprotein B levels</a> with <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D001053">Apolipoproteins</a>. Furthermore, <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33462484">Aspartate aminotransferase to alanine aminotransferase ratio</a> was mapped to <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D001224">Aspartic Acid</a>, and <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29875488">Basal Cell Adhesion Molecule levels</a> to <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D002477">Cells</a>. <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/37500982">Bone mineral density variability</a> was associated with <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D008903">Minerals</a>, and <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34814699">CD209 antigen levels</a> with <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D000941">Antigens</a>. <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33949668">COVID-19</a> was directly matched to <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D000086382">COVID-19</a>. Other notable associations include <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34648354">Cadherin-17 levels</a> with <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D015820">Cadherins</a>, <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38036781">Duodenal ulcer</a> with <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D004381">Duodenal Ulcer</a>, and <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23381943">End-stage coagulation</a> with <a href="https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?ui=D000090882">Thromboinflammation</a>. These findings highlight the diverse biological roles and clinical implications of the ABO blood group system.</p> <p>The gene is expressed in various tissues, including cardiac myocytes, heart, liver, colorectal adenocarcinoma, colon, adrenal gland, and fetal liver. Additionally, it is expressed in Burkitt’s lymphoma (Raji) cells.</p> <p>The mouse ortholog gene 80908, which corresponds to the human ortholog gene 28, is associated with several phenotypic abnormalities. These include abnormal skin morphology, which is observed in both sexes, as well as abnormal testis morphology and small testis, both of which are not observed in both sexes.</p> <p>The analyzed protein sequence has a GRAVY value of -0.079 (79.53rd percentile), indicating a relatively hydrophilic nature. It exhibits a charge of 8.53 at pH 7.0 (78.2nd percentile) and a median structural flexibility of 0.989 (10.59th percentile). The protein’s secondary structure is predicted to be 30.79% helix (38.93rd percentile), 40.96% sheet (88.64th percentile), and 22.32% turn (7.39th percentile). The instability index is 48.64 (52.49th percentile), with an isoelectric point of 9.14 (82.79th percentile). The protein has a length of 354 amino acids (38.72nd percentile) and a molecular weight of 40933.34 Da (40.73rd percentile). For more details on the sequence analysis, refer to the <a href="https://biopython.org/docs/1.75/api/Bio.SeqUtils.ProtParam.html">BioPython documentation</a>.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Checks</th> <th style="text-align: left">Answer</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Sentiment</td> <td style="text-align: left">neutral</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Ethical concerns</td> <td style="text-align: left">no</td> </tr> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Coherence</td> <td style="text-align: left">yes</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="unknown-mechanism"/><category term="cooccuring-genes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ABO description]]></summary></entry></feed>